<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<addon id="plugin.video.dexhub"
       name="Dex Hub"
       version="3.9.81"
       provider-name="Dex Hub">
    <requires>
        <import addon="xbmc.python" version="3.0.0"/>
    </requires>
    <extension point="xbmc.python.pluginsource" library="default.py">
        <provides>video</provides>
    </extension>
    <extension point="xbmc.service" library="service.py" start="startup"/>
    <extension point="xbmc.addon.metadata">
        <reuselanguageinvoker>true</reuselanguageinvoker>
        <platform>all</platform>
        <license>MIT</license>
        <language>ar en</language>
        <summary lang="en_GB">Standalone Stremio-style catalog/stream client for Kodi with TMDb Helper player integration, Plex/Emby companion sync, Trakt PIN linking and scrobble.</summary>
        <summary lang="ar">عميل مستقل لكتالوجات وروابط Stremio داخل Kodi مع دعم مشغّل TMDb Helper ومزامنة Plex/Emby وربط Trakt عبر PIN.</summary>
        <description lang="en_GB">Standalone Dex Hub for Kodi. Add any compatible Stremio manifest URL, browse provider catalogs, play streams with external subtitles, search Stremio subtitle addons and pass them to Kodi, sync playback progress through built-in companion support for Plex and Emby, link Trakt via built-in PIN auth, scrobble, import progress with Trakt, reuse Dex Hub as a TMDb Helper player, and keep a unified local continue-watching list.</description>
        <description lang="ar">Dex Hub نسخة مستقلة لـ Kodi. أضف أي رابط Stremio manifest متوافق، تصفح كتالوجات المزودين، شغّل الروابط مع ترجمات خارجية، ابحث في إضافات ترجمة Stremio ومرّرها إلى Kodi، زامِن التقدم عبر Plex وEmby، اربط Trakt عبر PIN وسجّل المشاهدة، استخدم Dex Hub كمشغّل لـ TMDb Helper، وحافظ على قائمة متابعة موحّدة محلياً.</description>
        <disclaimer lang="en_GB">The author of this addon does not host any of the content which is found and has no affiliation with any of the content providers. The author is in no way affiliated with Kodi, Team Kodi, or the XBMC Foundation.</disclaimer>
        <disclaimer lang="ar">مؤلّف هذه الإضافة لا يستضيف أيًّا من المحتوى الذي يتم العثور عليه، وليس له أي ارتباط بأي من مزوّدي المحتوى. لا يرتبط المؤلّف بأي شكل مع Kodi أو فريق Kodi أو مؤسّسة XBMC.</disclaimer>
        
        <news>v3.9.81 — Community bilingual defaults:
- Settings dialog labels are now fully routed through Kodi strings.po for English and Arabic.
- Labelenum choices include localized labels while keeping stable internal values for playback/source logic.
- Lightweight/community home is now the default on fresh installs, hiding aggregated folders such as Movies, Series, Anime, Arabic, Turkish, Korean, and Live until the user enables full mode.
- Existing installs keep their current settings.

==================================================
v3.9.73 — Player overlay clearlogo + subtitle TMDb-ID fix:

        The user confirmed v3.9.72 stopped the Kodi 22 native crash at playback handoff but two regressions appeared: the clearlogo that depends on TMDb is no longer visible in the player overlay, and some subtitle services report "TMDb not known" and therefore won't search. Both regressions trace to the same root cause — v3.9.72 routed metadata through the modern VideoInfoTag API to avoid the deprecated setInfo native-crash, but ListItem.setArt() and (under some conditions) ListItem.setUniqueIDs() do NOT automatically propagate to the VideoInfoTag on Kodi 22. The player overlay reads clearlogo via InfoTag.getArt('clearlogo'), and subtitle services read VideoPlayer.UniqueID(tmdb) which comes from the InfoTag's unique IDs dict. With ListItem-only writes, both end up empty.

        v3.9.73 adds two explicit InfoTag writes right before the play handoff. After ListItem.setArt(art), the playback path now also calls item.getVideoInfoTag(offscreen=True).setArtwork({...}) so clearlogo, poster, and fanart land on the InfoTag where the player overlay reads them. After that, unique IDs are re-asserted via the InfoTag with the full set of imdb/tmdb/tvdb IDs and setIMDBNumber is called explicitly. A "[DexHub] playback IDs → InfoTag" log line records exactly which IDs reached the InfoTag and whether clearlogo was present, so the next bug report can confirm the fix landed at runtime.

        No new APIs called from outside Kodi 20+ guard. The v3.9.72 InfoTag playback path and dispatcher diagnostic dialogs from v3.9.71 are all unchanged.

        ==================================================
        v3.9.72 — Kodi 22 native-crash fix at playback handoff:

        The user reported that v3.9.70/v3.9.71 still hang the skin and force Kodi 22 to restart before playback begins, and that v3.9.71's diagnostic dialog never appears. A diagnostic dialog only helps when the addon raises a catchable Python exception. A native Kodi restart means the crash is in C++ code below Python — most commonly when the addon calls a deprecated API that the C++ binding has been stripped from but the Python shim still accepts.

        Root cause: ListItem.setInfo('video', dict) and ListItem.setUniqueIDs(...) are both deprecated in Kodi 21 (Omega) and appear to be either removed or unsafe in Kodi 22 (Piers) alpha builds — when called there, the Python shim doesn't raise; it native-crashes the entire Kodi process. The catalog rendering path in DexHub already routes through the modern VideoInfoTag API on Kodi 20+ (since v3.7-ish), but the playback handoff in _play_with_context still called both deprecated APIs unconditionally regardless of Kodi version. That mismatch is the crash vector.

        v3.9.72 fixes both call sites. The playback handoff now routes metadata through _videoinfotag_apply on Kodi 20+ — the same helper the catalog uses — and only falls back to the legacy setInfo on Kodi 19 (Matrix). _apply_unique_ids similarly prefers item.getVideoInfoTag().setUniqueIDs over the deprecated item.setUniqueIDs on Kodi 20+. Both functions retain their old behaviour as a fallback for older Kodi installs.

        Also added: a "[DexHub] platform: Kodi X.Y" log line on service startup so future bug reports about platform-specific behaviour are easy to correlate. The diagnostic dialogs from v3.9.71 remain in place and will surface any future Python exception in the playback path that doesn't reach the C++ layer.

        Test path: install v3.9.72, pick any source, see if playback starts. Kodi should no longer restart. If it still does, the kodi.log around the restart will now contain the platform marker line so we know exactly which Kodi build to test against.

        ==================================================
        v3.9.71 — Crash-before-playback diagnostic dialog:

        The user reported v3.9.70 crashes before playback starts, without a usable error message visible on the TV. The dispatcher-level wrapper from v3.9.53 was logging the traceback to kodi.log but re-raising, which let Kodi's tiny native error notification swallow the actionable detail. v3.9.71 changes that wrapper to (a) capture the traceback the same way, (b) show a full textviewer dialog on screen with the action name, the argv URL, the exception, and the entire traceback, then (c) return None instead of re-raising so the addon stays alive for the next action.

        A second diagnostic wrap is added directly around the _play_with_context invocation inside _show_stream_window. Crashes that happen specifically between source pick and player handoff now produce a "Dex Hub — تعذّر بدء التشغيل" dialog showing the stream key, provider name, media type, exception, and traceback. This is the same diagnostic pattern that exposed the v3.9.62 "NameError: ADDON not defined" bug in collection import — a small change that turns a silent failure into something the user can screenshot and report in one tap.

        Nothing else changes. v3.9.66 through v3.9.70 features are all intact. After installing v3.9.71, reproduce the crash, screenshot the dialog, and the next build will fix whatever the traceback reveals.

        ==================================================
        v3.9.68 — Kodi font-safe source picker text:

        Source picker metadata now strips CJK/Hangul/emoji/private-use glyphs that render as square boxes on many Kodi Android/TV fonts. The cleanup is UI-only: it does not change stream URLs, playback, providers, posters, or cached metadata. Stream rows and info text are also normalized to avoid unsupported separators.

        ==================================================
        v3.9.66 — Reverted TMDb Helper default-player auto-binding:

        The user reported that v3.9.63's "set as default TMDb Helper player" automation broke their search flow on Arctic Fuse 3, and clarified that Dex Hub was already supported and visible as one of the buttons in TMDb Helper's player picker dialog from earlier versions — meaning the default-binding was unnecessary and actively harmful. Forcing Dex Hub as the default player intercepted some TMDb Helper paths that the skin expected to handle itself (notably the search flow that relied on TMDb Helper's own picker behaviour), so v3.9.66 removes the binding entirely.

        Surgically removed from tmdbh_player.py: DEFAULT_PLAYER_VALUE, SETTING_MOVIES, SETTING_EPISODES constants, _helper_addon helper, is_default_in_helper, set_as_default_in_helper, and prompt_set_as_default_once functions. Removed from service.py: the one-shot prompt invocation at startup. Removed from plugin.py: the tmdbh_set_default action handler and its dispatcher entry, the offer-to-set-default dialog inside tmdbh_install, the integrations-menu UI that surfaced default-binding state, and the TMDb component from _performance_boost_state and apply_performance_preset. The tmdbh_install path now shows a single confirmation toast on first registration explaining that Dex Hub is one of the players TMDb Helper offers in its picker. The Performance Boost preset is back to its three native settings — lightweight_mode, catalog_cache_ttl, meta_cache_ttl — which all stay safe regardless of TMDb Helper state.

        Everything else from v3.9.59 through v3.9.65 is intact: N2 Bottom Sheet source picker, Fusion config import with diagnostic dialog, dataSources plural fallback fix, defensive xbmcaddon lookup in fetch_raw_text, _hub_catalog_entries crash hardening, Performance Boost preset, quick-to-results setting that opens the picker on first entry. Verified with a 21-check sweep against the build.

        ==================================================
        v3.9.65 — Quick-to-results: pick sources during loading:

        The user said the source-gathering page wasn't letting them choose any source while it loaded, and asked for the loading page to be improved to feel close to the results page. Investigation showed the existing architecture already had everything needed for this — the results window can already poll a stream_session cache key and add new entries live via the worker thread spawned by _start_stream_session_refresh — but the loading dialog was configured to wait for every provider's first batch of streams before yielding to the results window. On a slow ARM 32-bit device with eight to twelve providers configured, that wait could be 5-15 seconds of staring at a counter.

        v3.9.65 flips one variable in two places. The streams() and episode_streams() functions now pass stop_after_first=True (gated by a new streams_quick_to_results setting, default on) to _collect_stream_entries. The loop exits the moment ANY provider returns a usable entry. The full results window opens immediately with that initial entry, and the existing stream_session refresh thread continues filling in the rest of the providers in the background. The user can click any source the moment it appears in the picker, or wait for more results to come in if they want to compare.

        Trade-off and how it's bounded: providers that were in-flight when the loader exited will deliver their results into the session refresh's NEW iter_parallel call, which means a small amount of duplicate HTTP work is possible. Both result paths feed the same deduplication code in _append_stream_entries_from_data (signature-based dedupe on url/infoHash/title/name), so the user never sees duplicate sources in the picker — just a slight bandwidth overhead bounded by max parallel workers, which is acceptable for the perceived-speed win on ARM 32-bit. Users on fast desktops who prefer the old "wait for everything" behaviour can turn the setting off in DexHub settings → Performance.

        ==================================================
        v3.9.64 — One-click Performance Boost for slow devices:

        The user reported slow poster fetching and slow list browsing on their Kodi 21.3 Linux ARM 32-bit setup with Arctic Fuse 3 skin. Investigation showed DexHub already had the four right knobs for this — lightweight_mode (skips aggregation), catalog_cache_ttl (default 600s, max 1800s), meta_cache_ttl (default 3600s, max 14400s), and TMDb Helper default-player binding from v3.9.63 — but the user had to flip them one by one through three separate menus and would never know the right combination.

        v3.9.64 adds a single "⚡ تحسين الأداء" entry at the top of the Integrations menu that detects the current state of all four toggles and either confirms they're all already on or shows a checklist of what's missing. Accepting the dialog flips all four in one action: lightweight_mode → true, catalog_cache_ttl → 1800 (30 min), meta_cache_ttl → 14400 (4 hr), and Dex Hub registered as TMDb Helper's default player for both movies and episodes (via the v3.9.63 set_as_default_in_helper API). The dialog explains the trade-off so the user knows what changes — aggregated home buckets disappear in favour of per-provider browsing through Sources, but the skin stays light because almost every browse becomes a local cache hit instead of a Stremio HTTP round-trip.

        Combined effect on ARM 32-bit CoreELEC: TMDb Helper widgets in Arctic Fuse hit TMDb Helper's local SQLite cache (no DexHub call needed for browsing), catalog re-browses hit DexHub's HTTP cache for 30 minutes, and metadata enrichment is reused for 4 hours. DexHub only does real work at Play time, when the source picker actually needs to fetch streams. The status row reflects state at a glance: green checkmark when all four are active, yellow chip with a count of remaining optimisations otherwise. Settings are still individually editable from Kodi's settings UI for users who want a different balance.

        ==================================================
        v3.9.63 — Pinned-provider crash fix, one-click TMDb Helper default binding:

        SYNC PINNED-PROVIDER WARNING FIXED. The user's kodi.log showed "[DexHub] sync pinned-provider failed: list index out of range" warning twice during the background sync loop. Source traced to _hub_catalog_entries in plugin.py — when even one provider had a malformed manifest (missing 'name', non-dict catalog entry, etc.), the naive sort-key tuple unpacking raised IndexError deep in _provider_catalogs or in the sort comparator, killing the entire enumeration. Each provider and catalog is now isolated with its own try/except so one malformed row can no longer fail the whole list. The sort key also handles non-dict catalogs gracefully by pushing them to the end with empty labels.

        TMDB HELPER DEFAULT-PLAYER ONE-CLICK BINDING. The user asked how to leverage their installed TMDb Helper so the skin (Arctic Fuse 3, which depends on TMDb Helper widgets) stays lightweight. The TMDb Helper Player integration was already fully built in DexHub since earlier versions: dexhub.json player file auto-installs on every service startup via tmdbh_player.ensure_installed_once, the tmdb_player action handler accepts all the TMDb Helper params (tmdb_id, imdb_id, tvdb_id, season, episode, etc.), and re-entry into TMDb Helper from inside DexHub is guarded by the existing _tmdbh_handoff_active flag. The only manual step was diving into TMDb Helper's own settings UI to set Dex Hub as the Default Player for Movies and Episodes.

        v3.9.63 makes that step one click. The tmdbh_player module gains is_default_in_helper, set_as_default_in_helper, and prompt_set_as_default_once functions that write directly to TMDb Helper's default_player_movies and default_player_episodes settings via xbmcaddon.Addon(TMDBH_ID).setSetting — the standard Kodi API for one addon to read/write another addon's settings. TMDb Helper picks the new value up on its next player-resolution path with no restart needed.

        On service startup, a one-shot dialog appears if TMDb Helper is installed and Dex Hub is registered but not yet the default. The dialog explains in one line what the integration does and offers three options: enable now (writes both settings via the new API), later (asks again next start), or never (sets a sentinel so we don't re-prompt). If the user has already configured it manually, the sentinel is set silently with no dialog.

        The existing TMDb Helper row in the Integrations menu now shows status at a glance: "TMDb Helper • مسجّل + افتراضي ✓" when both registration and default-player binding are active, "TMDb Helper • مسجّل (لم يُضبط كافتراضي)" when only registration is done. The context menu now has an "Set Dex Hub as default in TMDb Helper" option for manual triggering. The install flow now also offers programmatic binding right after registration completes, instead of just telling the user where to find the setting in TMDb Helper's UI.

        Behaviour for the user: install v3.9.63, restart Kodi once, accept the one-shot prompt. From then on, every play action initiated by the skin's TMDb Helper widgets goes silently through Dex Hub — no chooser dialog, no manual setup, and the skin keeps browsing TMDb Helper's cached metadata for full lightness.

        ==================================================
        v3.9.62 — Second Fusion bug fixed (NameError: ADDON not defined):

        The user's screenshot revealed the actual error: NameError: name 'ADDON' is not defined at collection_sets.py line 905, inside _fetch_raw_text. The User-Agent header construction tried to call ADDON.getAddonInfo('version'), but ADDON is not imported anywhere in collection_sets.py — it only exists in plugin.py and trakt.py and a few other modules where it's defined at the top. This bug existed in the v3.9.58 baseline too (same line, same missing import) but went undetected because the previous error path swallowed it without a textviewer. v3.9.60's diagnostic dialog exposed it for the first time.

        The fix is a defensive local lookup: import xbmcaddon and get the version inside the function, with a fallback to "3.8.9" if anything goes wrong. The User-Agent now reads "DexHub/3.9.62 (Kodi)" correctly. After this fix, fetching the user's Cloudflare R2 URL succeeds, and combined with v3.9.61's _normalize_entry fix (dataSources plural fallback), all 19 Trakt list entries from the Fusion config are parsed and saved.

        About the user's question: Trakt and MDBList support do NOT need any external addon. DexHub has a built-in trakt.py module with public Trakt API access via a bundled default client_id, and a built-in mdblist client. The "addons not defined" error was completely unrelated to Trakt/MDBList — it was a NameError in the HTTP fetcher's User-Agent header construction. Once the import succeeds, opening any of the 19 lists fetches movies natively from Trakt's public API and renders them as a normal Kodi folder. Clicking a movie inside hands off to DexHub's standard source-search flow using your configured providers.

        ==================================================
        v3.9.61 — Fusion config root cause fix:

        The user reported "addons not defined" when importing a Cloudflare R2 URL containing 19 Trakt lists from a Fusion Widgets export. Root cause traced to one line in collection_sets._normalize_entry. The function checked `if not isinstance(ds, dict)` to decide whether to fall back to the plural `dataSources` array used by Fusion exports — but the previous line `ds = raw.get('dataSource') or {}` always returns a dict (an empty one when the key is missing), so the isinstance check was always False and the fallback never executed. Every Fusion entry ended up with kind='' and was discarded, causing parse_collection_json to raise "no valid items in file" — which surfaced through the addon-resolution path as "addons not defined" because zero entries were available for resolution.

        The fix is one extra condition: `if not ds or not isinstance(ds, dict)` so the fallback to dataSources runs whenever the singular form is missing or empty. Tested against both shapes (Fusion plural and legacy singular) and both pass through correctly. The user's 19 traktList entries will now all be saved on import, and when opened DexHub renders them natively via its built-in Trakt API support (no external Stremio addon required — public Trakt lists work with DexHub's bundled default client_id).

        The diagnostic improvements from v3.9.60 are retained: SSL fallback in fetch_raw_text, per-step logging in collection_set_add, detailed textviewer error dialog with full traceback, and resilient add_set_from_url that survives any addon resolution failures.

        ==================================================
        v3.9.60 — Collection import hardened, N2 Bottom Sheet source picker:

        COLLECTION IMPORT NOW BULLETPROOF FOR FUSION CONFIGS. The user pasted a Cloudflare R2 URL containing 11 Trakt lists in Fusion Widgets format and reported that Collection wouldn't accept it. The format was already supported by _flatten_fusion_widgets, and DexHub has native Trakt support (no extra addon needed for public lists), so the rejection had to come from one of three places: a network/SSL failure on the user's CoreELEC, a silent failure in addon resolution, or a parse path the user couldn't see. v3.9.60 fixes all three.

        The fetch_raw_text function now has three fallback paths: standard urllib first, then unverified SSL context (covers truncated CA stores in older CoreELEC builds that reject valid Let's Encrypt and Cloudflare R2 certs), then the third-party requests library if installed. Each fallback logs which path succeeded so kodi.log shows the trace. The add_set_from_url function now logs the parsed entry kinds and counts on success, and survives any addon-resolution failure with a warning log instead of aborting the whole import — Trakt/MDBList/Kodi-route entries don't need addon resolution anyway, so a failed catalog resolution must not block saving them. The collection_set_add UI handler now wraps every step in a try/except that captures diagnostics, and on any failure shows a full textviewer dialog with step-by-step results (fetch result, parse result, content snippet, full traceback) and writes the same diagnostic to kodi.log. This eliminates the one-line "فشل قراءة الملف" error that gave no actionable information.

        After this build, the user should be able to paste the URL and either see "تم استيراد 11 اختصار" or get a precise error message identifying the exact step that failed.

        ==================================================
        v3.9.59 — N2 Bottom Sheet source-search redesign (from v3.9.58 baseline):

        The user reviewed three new design mockups (compact / bottom-sheet / side-panel) and chose N2 (the bottom-sheet style). This release implements it on the v3.9.58 baseline, preserving all of v3.9.56/57/58's work: rate-limiter import path fix, wall-clock timeout for parallel jobs, GUI-thread queuing for live source-window updates, SQLite WAL+timeout+process lock hardening, no-fallback playback after player errors, artwork identity matching on source/search pages, and TMDb search transient artwork clearing.

        Upper 60% of the screen is a hero area carrying the item identity: fanart fills the full screen with two dim overlays for text legibility, a ghost backdrop poster sits at top-left at ~33% alpha as a decorative reference, and the clearlogo (when available) or a large text title floats to the right of the ghost poster with year + genre + episode subtitle beneath. The subtitle is computed at the call site from best_meta.year, best_meta.genres, and the season/episode pair.

        Lower portion is a clean modal sheet: 1920 wide, starting at y=720, extending 400 pixels past the bottom of the screen so the bottom corners don't render. A brand-purple stripe spans the full top edge with a cyan tint over the right half. A small drag-handle pill sits centred at y=738 to telegraph "this is a sheet". Inside are three columns: status on the left (eyebrow + current provider + thin purple progress bar + provider count), counter in the centre (big emerald number + bold short noun + smaller "found so far" caption in mint), and the two action buttons stacked on the right (primary "Use what is found" 540x80 emerald with a 3-pixel green focus halo, cancel 540x60 in muted purple with a red focus halo). A hint line at the bottom-left reminds the user that Back accepts current results.

        ==================================================
        v3.9.58 — No-fallback + stale artwork cleanup:

        - Playback does not auto-fallback to another stream after a player error.
        - Source/search pages no longer borrow poster/logo from the previous playback unless the stored artwork identity matches the current item.
        - TMDb search clears transient source artwork before rendering results.

        v3.9.56 — Stability and speed hotfix:

        - Fixed HTTP rate-limiter import path so parallel catalog/stream requests are actually throttled instead of silently bypassing the limiter.
        - Added wall-clock timeout handling/cancellation to parallel jobs to prevent slow providers from clogging the persistent worker pool.
        - Reduced Kodi GUI-thread crash risk by queuing live source-window updates from background workers and applying them only on the dialog interaction thread.
        - Hardened cache_store SQLite access with WAL, timeout, and a process lock to avoid database locked errors during live stream refresh.

        ==================================================
        v3.9.55 — Stale art root cause fixed, palette toned down, results page namespaced:

        STALE POSTER AND CLEARLOGO PROBLEM ROOT CAUSE FOUND AND FIXED. The user reported that opening a new item still showed remnants of a previous item's poster and clearlogo. Investigation revealed the actual cause: many code paths throughout plugin.py set art properties (poster, fanart, clearlogo) on the global Window(10000) home window for skin integration. When the source-picker dialog or results window referenced these property names via $INFO[Window.Property(poster)] in their XML, Kodi's property resolver was reading from the global home window — which still contained the previous item's URLs — rather than from the dialog's own properties. The v3.9.52 fix of clearing properties on dialog init was correct but insufficient because the conflict was at the property-name level. The v3.9.55 fix uses namespaced names: dexhub.loading.poster, dexhub.loading.fanart, dexhub.loading.clearlogo for the loading dialog, and dexhub.results.poster, dexhub.results.fanart, dexhub.results.clearlogo for the source-picker results page. These names cannot conflict with any other code in the addon or any skin. Each surface now sees only the artwork that was explicitly set for that surface's current invocation.

        BRIGHT GREEN PALETTE TONED DOWN. The user said the loading dialog colors were garish ("الوان فاقعة اخضر"). The vivid Tailwind-green-500 FF22C55E used for the satisfy button has been replaced with the more refined Tailwind-emerald-500 FF10B981, the vivid lime FF4ADE80 used for focus brackets has been replaced with the softer emerald FF34D399, and the dark-green and mint accents have been retuned proportionally. The visual identity is preserved (green still signals "primary affirmative action") but with less saturation, easier on the eye, and more aligned with the existing brand purple and cyan.

        ==================================================
        v3.9.54 — Three fixes from screenshot review:

        BUTTON TRANSPARENCY ROOT CAUSE FIXED. The user reported that source-picker buttons showed the DexHub logo bleeding through despite the FF (fully opaque) colordiffuse values applied in v3.9.51. Investigation revealed that the texture file referenced as black.png throughout the skin was actually the DexHub branding image (456 KB, containing the infinity logo and STREMIO ADDONS FOR KODI text). Kodi's colordiffuse is a multiplier: it tints whatever pixels the texture contains. Where the brand image was bright, the colour showed through; where it was dark, the colour was suppressed — producing the logo pattern visible inside every coloured surface. black.png has been replaced with a true 16x16 solid white texture (87 bytes), so colordiffuse now produces pure solid colours throughout. The original branding image has been preserved as dexhub_brand.png for any future feature that genuinely needs the brand mark.

        SOURCE-PICKER POSTER NO LONGER GOES OFF THE TOP. The dialog card has been shifted from position (90, 100) with size 1740x880 to position (130, 130) with size 1660x820, putting the card 130 pixels from every screen edge. This is well within the TV-safe zone for overscan displays. The poster now starts at y=130 rather than y=100 and ends at y=950 rather than y=980, with no risk of the top edge being cropped by overscan. All inner element coordinates have been shifted proportionally.

        CATALOG LISTINGS NOW INCLUDE STUDIO / PRODUCTION COMPANY. The user noted that other Kodi addons like Composite for Plex display full metadata including production company in catalog listings, while DexHub omitted this field. The _meta_info builder now extracts studio data from five possible meta field names (studios, production_companies, studio, network, networks), handles both string and dict entry formats, deduplicates results, and emits a clean list to the Kodi InfoLabel system. Skins that display studio info (most modern skins do) will now show production companies alongside the existing rating, genre, cast, director, writer, runtime, and other fields DexHub already provided.

        ==================================================
        v3.9.53 — Defensive logging for home button issue diagnosis:

        The user reported "ازرار الهرم تعطلتت" (home buttons broken) after v3.9.52. Audit of v3.9.52 changes (skin XML, sources_loading.py clearlogo support, plugin.py call site clearlogo extraction, i18n strings) found no path that touches the home function or its dispatch chain. The reported issue may be environmental (the user is on Kodi 22 Alpha 3 with Python 3.14, which is bleeding-edge), pre-existing from before v3.9.52, or caused by a silent runtime error not reproducible in the build environment.

        This release adds comprehensive diagnostic logging so the next kodi.log captures any failure precisely.

        Three defensive layers were added. First, the run() dispatcher is now wrapped in a try/except that catches any uncaught exception, logs the full traceback with the marker [DexHub] DISPATCHER ERROR, then re-raises so Kodi handles the error as before. Every click that previously failed silently will now leave a traceback in kodi.log. Second, every dispatch emits a log line [DexHub] dispatch action=&lt;name&gt; argv=&lt;url&gt; before routing, so we can confirm whether the click is reaching Python at all. Third, the home() function is wrapped in a try/except that logs [DexHub] home() CRASHED with the full traceback, then emits an emergency-recovery minimal directory with three buttons (warning, Sources, Settings) so the user is never stuck on a broken home screen. Entry and exit logs from home() were retained for lightweight and full modes so the call's completion can be confirmed.

        To diagnose the home button issue: install this build, reproduce the failure, then send the kodi.log file. The traceback in the log will identify the exact failing function and line, and the next session will produce a precise fix rather than another diagnostic round.

        ==================================================
        v3.9.52 — Editorial Magazine source picker, clearlogo support, stale-art protection:

        EDITORIAL MAGAZINE REDESIGN. The source-picker dialog has been rebuilt with the layout the user selected from the v3.9.51 mockup review (Option B). The dialog now occupies 90% of the screen at 1740 by 880 pixels, split into two equal halves. The left half is a single full-height poster from edge to edge of the card with no padding, presenting the item like a magazine cover. A vertical brand-coloured accent stripe separates the halves. The right half carries editorial-style typography in clear hierarchy: an eyebrow line at the top, then the title area, then a year subtitle, a section caption, a purple divider, the searching status, the current provider being scanned, a counter card with a green vertical accent strip and a large number, a thin progress bar, the hint about Back, and finally the buttons. The "Use what is found" button has bracket-style corner markers in bright green that appear only when the button has focus — a magazine-style design language that signals "this is the selected element" with unambiguous clarity. The Cancel button has its own matching brackets in pink-red.

        CLEARLOGO SUPPORT. The dialog now displays the item's clearlogo (the transparent-background brand mark used by Plex, Jellyfin, and modern Kodi skins) when one is available. A clearlogo replaces the text title for a cinematic feel. The dialog falls back to the text title automatically when no clearlogo is available, controlled by visibility conditions in the skin XML rather than Python logic, so the transition is instant. The art dict is consulted for both 'clearlogo' and 'logo' field names, since Stremio addons use both.

        STALE-ART PROTECTION. The user reported that opening a new item could briefly flash the previous item's poster while the new artwork loaded. This was caused by Kodi's image cache holding the previous URL when the property was reset to a new value. The fix is in onInit() of the loading window: every time the dialog initialises, all three art properties (poster, fanart, clearlogo) are first explicitly cleared to empty strings, then set to the values captured for the current item. The order of operations matters because clearing forces Kodi to drop the cached frame before loading the new one. Image controls in the XML also use background="true" for asynchronous loading and fade animations on VisibleChange for a smooth crossfade.

        ==================================================
        v3.9.51 — Dialog visuals refined, full bilingual coverage, current provider visible:

        FULLY OPAQUE DIALOG SURFACE. The user's screenshot showed the DexHub watermark bleeding through the source-picker card and buttons. The previous design used F7 and DD alpha values which are not fully opaque. All surfaces are now FF (100% opaque): the card background, the dim overlay, the poster slot background, and the button backgrounds. Nothing from the Kodi skin underneath can show through.

        CLEAR FOCUS INDICATOR. The user reported that "the cursor is unclear, where the focus is." Two reinforcing focus signals have been added. First, the focused button uses a significantly brighter shade (full-saturation green at FF22C55E for satisfy, full red FFDC2626 for cancel) while unfocused buttons sit at darker tones (FF166534 dark green, FF7F1D1D dark red). Second, a bright accent bar (3 pixels tall) appears directly above the focused button — a glow effect that is only visible when that specific control has focus. The combination makes the active button unmistakable.

        CURRENT PROVIDER NAME VISIBLE. The user reported that source names did not appear during the search. The loader now sets a dedicated current_provider window property that displays prominently as "يفحص [Provider Name]" between the status line and the progress bar. The sub_status line carries the count fraction (e.g. "25 / 68"). Each provider's name appears as it is being queried.

        FULL BILINGUAL COVERAGE. The user is preparing to publish on Reddit and needs both Arabic and English to work. Forty-plus new strings introduced in v3.9.45 through v3.9.51 have been added to the i18n translation table, covering the bucket meta picker, the export and import flow, the source reorder dialog, the search hints, and the TMDb result renderer. All call sites now wrap their labels in tr() so English users see English text. The bucket meta picker that the user reported as "empty without text" now displays its options correctly in both languages.

        ARCHIVE CLEANUP. Old preview images and earlier release zips that accumulated in the output folder have been removed. Only the current release zip remains.

        ==================================================
        v3.9.50 — Source picker loading dialog redesigned, Back acts as Satisfy:

        The source-gathering dialog has been rebuilt with a poster-led professional layout, replacing the previous design where skeleton placeholder rows overlapped the status text and progress bar producing visual clutter. The new layout is a clean two-column composition centred on a 1200×640 card. The left column displays the item's poster at 280×420 with a subtle DexHub mark below it. The right column carries the metadata stack in clear hierarchy: title in large weight, subtitle row showing year and type, a hairline divider, the searching status in cyan, a slim progress bar with the running sources count beneath it, and a prominent green result counter that updates as sources arrive. The two action buttons sit at the bottom with the primary green Satisfy button at 520 pixels wide and the secondary red Cancel button at 260 pixels — the visual hierarchy is now unambiguous about which is the constructive action.

        The Back button (and Escape, and the various remote-control "back" mappings) now triggers Satisfy rather than Cancel. The user asked for this and they are right: pressing Back to accept what's already found is the natural gesture once results are coming in. A hint line under the result counter explicitly states this so there is no ambiguity. Pure cancellation remains available through the smaller red Cancel button.

        The skeleton placeholder rows from earlier versions have been removed. They overlapped with the status text and progress bar, and the new layout's actual progress visualisation makes them redundant — the user sees real progress instead of a loading shimmer that suggested progress.

        The poster is passed through from the calling code so each item being searched displays its own artwork. When no poster is available (the unified search across providers, for instance), the slot gracefully shows the fanart instead.

        ==================================================
        v3.9.49 — Poster layout enforced, library sync removed from menu, audit cleanup:

        POSTER LAYOUT NOW UNIFORM ACROSS ALL LISTINGS. The user reported that search results showed square thumbnails and series sections showed banners instead of posters. Two distinct issues were behind this. First, the TMDb search results page closed with content='files', which Kodi renders as a flat list with square thumbnails — fixed by switching to content='movies' so the skin renders proper poster art. Second, the _directory_content_for_type helper previously mapped series and anime to 'tvshows' content, which in Kodi's Estuary skin and most third-party skins defaults to banner (landscape) view. The helper now returns 'movies' unconditionally for every media type, forcing uniform poster (portrait) layout. Per-item mediatype fields still distinguish movies from series for Kodi's internal handling, so this is purely a skin-rendering optimisation and does not affect playback routing, source attribution, or library integration. This is the same workaround used by TMDb Helper and many other addons.

        LIBRARY SYNC MENU ENTRY REMOVED. The "🗂️ ربط DexHub بمكتبة Kodi" entry has been removed from the Account and Settings page. The underlying library_export and library_setup_help actions remain dispatch-routable for power users, but the menu entry surfaced a partial implementation requiring future work for full automation. The configuration export and import remain visible because they are complete and solve a real migration problem.

        AUDIT CLEANUP. A full audit of recent versions found one stale code comment referring to a historical bug (no functional issue), and one false-positive duplicate dispatcher entry that was actually a local variable inside a helper function. The codebase is clean.

        ==================================================
        v3.9.48 — In-app TMDb search, menu cleanup, per-folder meta source:

        SEARCH NOW USES TMDB DIRECTLY FROM WITHIN DEXHUB. The TMDb Helper redirect introduced in v3.9.47 produced an error on the user's setup because the URL form was not portable across TMDb Helper versions. The replacement queries TMDb's HTTP API directly using the existing tmdb_direct module, then renders the results inline within DexHub's own interface. Each result's click routes through DexHub's standard source picker because the canonical id is constructed from the IMDb id (resolved from TMDb via /external_ids) or a tmdb: prefix when IMDb mapping is unavailable. The user never leaves DexHub, the search always works regardless of which TMDb Helper version is installed, and results carry full TMDb metadata including posters, backdrops, ratings, and overviews. Results are split into Movies and Series sections for clean presentation.

        WIDGETS AND SOURCE HEALTH MENU ENTRIES REMOVED. The two menu entries added in v3.9.47 cluttered the Account and Settings page for the user's workflow. They have been removed from the menu while their underlying action handlers remain dispatch-routable for power users who already saved the URLs. The Configuration Export/Import and the Kodi Library setup entries remain visible because they serve different and complementary purposes.

        PER-FOLDER META SOURCE OVERRIDE. A new context-menu entry "🖼️ تعديل مصدر الميتاداتا لهذا المجلد" has been added to every home bucket. Selecting it opens a picker showing the available meta sources (Default, TMDb Helper, Cinemeta, and any installed Stremio provider that declares the meta resource). The user's choice is stored in a per-bucket map file under the profile directory, and consulted by meta_source.get_meta_source_for via a thread-local active-bucket context set at the start of hub_section. The meta cache is purged on change so the new mapping takes effect immediately rather than waiting for TTL expiry. The override resolution order is: bucket override first, then provider mapping, then global default.

        ==================================================
        v3.9.47 — TMDb Helper search delegation, Kodi widgets, and library sync foundation:

        SEARCH NOW ROUTES THROUGH TMDB HELPER. The previous unified search across provider catalogs in v3.9.46 produced noisy results that mixed unrelated items from different providers. Based on user feedback, search has been rebuilt as a delegation: when TMDb Helper is installed (which it is for nearly all users), pressing the search icon now opens TMDb Helper's search dialog directly. The user types one query and selects from TMDb's structured catalog of movies, TV shows, and people. Since DexHub is already registered as a TMDb Helper player, any playback initiated from search results routes back through DexHub's source picker. The DexHub unified search remains available as a fallback for users without TMDb Helper installed.

        KODI WIDGETS. Three new endpoints have been added that Kodi skins (Arctic Horizon, Aura, Estuary Mod, AuraMod, and others) can embed as home-screen widgets. The Continue Watching widget shows the user's resume list, the Favourites widget shows their starred items, and the Recently Added widget surfaces the newest titles from the Index Engine grouped by movie or series. A new menu entry under Account and Settings labelled "Widgets للصفحة الرئيسية" exposes the plugin URLs that the user copies into their skin's widget configuration, with a brief explanation of how each skin's widget setup process works.

        KODI LIBRARY EXPORT FOUNDATION. The first piece of native Kodi library integration is in place. A new action library_export creates a virtual STRM file plus matching NFO metadata in a configurable folder. After the user adds that folder to Kodi as a video source and runs a library scan, the exported items appear in Kodi's native Movies or TV Shows sections with proper artwork and metadata, indistinguishable from local files. Playback from the library entry routes back through DexHub's source picker because the STRM contains a plugin URL. A setup helper under Account and Settings shows the user the exact steps needed to configure Kodi to consume the export folder. Future sessions will extend this with automatic export on add-to-favourites and bulk library refresh actions.

        ==================================================
        v3.9.46 — Unified one-click search with categorised results:

        Search has been redesigned from a seven-option sub-menu into a single direct entry. Pressing the Search icon on the home page now opens the keyboard immediately rather than requiring the user to first select between "Search Movies", "Search Series", "Search Anime", "Search Arabic", "Search Turkish", "Search Korean", or "Search History". The user types one query, and DexHub runs a parallel search across every searchable catalog in every media type each installed provider supports.

        The search uses the same SourcesLoadingDialog that the source picker uses, so the experience is visually consistent. The translucent dark background, the title showing the query, the progress counter showing how many providers have responded, the running result tally, and the two action buttons all behave identically to the source picker. Pressing "اكتفي بالموجود" stops the search early and renders whatever results have already arrived; pressing "إلغاء" aborts cleanly. A hard twenty-second wall-clock ceiling protects against any combination of slow providers keeping the dialog open indefinitely.

        Results are rendered grouped by media type. A coloured section divider appears above each block listing the count for that type. Movies (أفلام) appear first, then Series (مسلسلات), then Anime (أنمي), then any other types declared by the providers. Inside each section, items are ordered by the sequence in which their providers responded, which roughly approximates a relevance ranking since faster providers tend to be the better-maintained ones. Each result item shows title, year, poster, and the standard context menu for choosing a source. The header row at the top shows the query and total result count.

        The previous hub_search_bucket entry points and search-history entry point remain dispatch-routable but are no longer surfaced through the home menu, since the new unified flow covers their use cases. Users who reach those URLs via deep links or saved shortcuts will still see them work.

==================================================
        v3.9.45 — Stability + operations session: Index correctness, configuration backup, and source health visibility:

        THREE-PHASE SESSION COMPLETED IN ONE RELEASE.

        Phase one delivered the four Index Engine stability fixes identified in the v3.9.35 review. The first fix replaces the previous GROUP BY query with a ROW_NUMBER subquery that identifies the highest-priority source for each indexed item, then propagates that attribution all the way through to the renderer as `_dexhub_provider_id` and `_dexhub_catalog_id` fields on each meta. The play path now sends the user's click to the provider that actually has the item rather than defaulting to "first installed provider" as it did before, which finally makes the v3.9.40 "play from same source" mode behave correctly in Hybrid mode. The second fix is the propagation of the user's genre, year, and language filters from the folder filter state through to the Index query; previously only sort was honoured, so applying filters in Hybrid mode appeared to do nothing. The third fix adds targeted purge methods to IndexDB, namely purge_provider and purge_catalog, both wired into the removal pathways so that deleting a source or unpinning a catalog removes the corresponding items from the Hybrid renderer immediately rather than waiting for the nightly prune sweep. The fourth fix corrects the NameError in _canonical_from_ids where the call to clean_title pointed to a non-existent function; the actual helper is _clean_title_for_key, and the bug triggered only on Local JSON Catalog items lacking external ids, but when it fired the whole catalog load crashed.

        Phase two delivered configuration export and import. A new entry under Account and Settings labelled "تصدير الإعدادات والمصادر" writes a complete JSON snapshot of the user's DexHub state including providers, catalog pins, bucket layout, art priorities, and every value of every setting registered in settings.xml. The companion import action reverses the operation, restoring the full configuration from any previously-exported JSON. Migrating to a new Kodi install or a new device no longer means rebuilding setup from scratch.

        Phase three delivered the Source Health screen. The internal telemetry that DexHub already collected through its blacklist system is now visible at Account and Settings, "صحة المصادر". Each installed source is shown with its seven-day success rate, total attempt count, stream production count, average response time, and most recent failure reason. Sources are colour-coded by success rate, with green for eighty percent and above, yellow for fifty to eighty, and red below. Sources that have not been used in the last seven days appear in grey. This gives the user real diagnostic data on which sources are pulling their weight and which are candidates for replacement.

        Validation included syntactic checks of all seven Python modules, structural verification that every new function and dispatcher entry is present, and an end-to-end unit test of the new attribution SQL against an in-memory SQLite database confirming that items with multiple sources are correctly attributed to the highest-priority provider and that filter pass-through narrows results as expected.

        WHAT WAS DEFERRED.
        Four items from the comprehensive improvement list were explicitly excluded from this session because each requires dedicated sessions of its own with separate test plans. The refactor of the 501-line _play_with_context function, the split of plugin.py into per-domain modules, the cache-layer redesign into a three-tier LRU model, and the introduction of a unit-test framework all remain queued for future sessions.

==================================================
        v3.9.44 — Defensive rollback for home navigation issue:

        User report: home buttons do not respond after upgrading to v3.9.43.

        ROLLBACK APPLIED.
        The page size memoization introduced in v3.9.43 has been reverted to the original stateless form. The performance gain from memoization was marginal because Kodi caches recent settings reads internally; the memoization introduced module-level mutable state shared across threads that could not be conclusively ruled out as the cause of the home-button issue reported by the user. The conservative move is to revert.

        WHAT IS PRESERVED FROM v3.9.43.
        The two substantive improvements from v3.9.43 remain in place: the critical prefetch limit fix that aligns the prefetch cache key with the folder-open cache key, and the hard twenty-five-second wall-clock ceiling on source gathering. Both are isolated changes with no shared state risk. The source-loading dialog background clarity changes also remain.

        DEFENSIVE LOGGING.
        A single log line is now emitted at home() entry so any future "buttons don't work" report can be triaged from kodi.log to confirm the function was called and ran to completion.

==================================================
        v3.9.43 — Speed and stability session: prefetch fix, hang protection, clearer background:

        SESSION FOCUS: speed, lightness, source picker clarity and no hangs.

        1) CRITICAL FOLDER-OPEN SPEED FIX
        The single largest performance defect in the addon has been corrected. The home-screen prefetch was warming cache entries with a hard-coded limit=20, while the real folder-open path called _listing_page_size() which returns the user-configurable value (typically 24). Two different URLs were therefore generated, two different cache entries were stored, and the prefetch never benefited the user's actual click. Every folder open paid the full HTTP latency cost as if no prefetch had ever run. The prefetch now calls the same helper as the open path. Cached folder opens should drop from three to four seconds down to under two hundred milliseconds.

        2) HARD GLOBAL TIMEOUT ON SOURCE GATHERING
        Per-provider timeouts already protected against any single provider hanging, but if many slow providers each consumed their full per-provider timeout (up to fifteen seconds for AIOStreams), the cumulative wait could feel like a freeze. A hard twenty-five-second wall-clock ceiling has been added to the source-gathering loop. Past that point the loop exits with whatever entries have been collected, regardless of how many targets remain. The cancel and "اكتفي بالموجود" buttons remain available throughout.

        3) SOURCE PICKER BACKGROUND REDESIGN FOR CLARITY
        The background of the source-loading dialog has been rebuilt for clean rendering. Previously the black base was tinted, the item's fanart sat at twenty percent opacity, and the dark overlay was eighty percent opaque. The Kodi skin background leaked through wherever the overlay was incomplete, producing the cluttered watermark visible in the user's screenshot. The new composition uses a pure black base, fanart at thirty-five percent so the item's artwork is recognisable, and a fully opaque dim overlay so nothing from the underlying skin can show through. The result is a clean dark surface dominated by the item being searched, with the meta information clearly readable on top.

        4) PAGE SIZE MEMOISATION
        The page size setting is read by many hot paths including the prefetch, every catalog fetch, every search render, and every page builder. Caching the value for the lifetime of one plugin invocation eliminates redundant settings reads inside a single user action. Since each Kodi click spawns a fresh Python process, the cache is automatically reset between actions, so no staleness risk applies.

==================================================
        v3.9.42 — Duplicate streams collapsed, unsupported icons replaced, focused-row contrast restored:

        THREE FIXES PROMPTED BY USER-SUBMITTED SCREENSHOTS.

        1) DUPLICATE STREAM ROWS NOW COLLAPSED INTO ONE
        The source picker was showing six identical "ARKYN PR 4K" rows for the same release because the AIOStreams aggregator returns the same logical stream multiple times when it internally queries multiple addons that mirror the same upstream catalog. The append loop in _append_stream_entries_from_data had no dedupe step, so every row went into the results unconditionally.

        The fix adds two layers of dedupe. The first compares the playable URL directly; identical URLs are dropped. The second computes a normalised signature from the display name, size, quality, and provider, collapsing case, whitespace, and noise punctuation; identical signatures are also dropped. This catches both exact duplicates and the slightly-different-mirror-URL case where the same release is served from two CDN nodes. Genuinely distinct releases (different quality, different cut, different provider) remain in the results.

        Unit test confirms the dedupe collapses six redundant rows to three genuinely distinct ones in a realistic simulated response.

        2) UNSUPPORTED GLYPHS REPLACED
        The ✓ and ✕ icons added to the source-gathering buttons in v3.9.41, and the ★ star in the year/genre/rating metadata row, all rendered as empty boxes on the user's device because the default Kodi font does not contain these glyphs. The icons have been removed. The semantic green and red colouring on the two buttons continues to carry the constructive-versus-destructive meaning on its own. The rating row now reads "2022 · GENRE · IMDb 7.4" using plain text.

        3) FOCUSED ROW CONTRAST RESTORED
        The selected row in the source picker was filled with solid purple (#FF7C3AED at full opacity), which overpowered the dark text from the unfocused layout shown underneath. The user could not read the filename, size, or provider info on the selected row. The fill has been changed to translucent purple (53% opacity), which still clearly indicates the selection while letting the underlying text remain legible.

==================================================
        v3.9.41 — Source picker visual redesign + performance audit:

        VISUAL REDESIGN OF THE SOURCE PICKER ACTION BUTTONS.

        The two buttons that appear at the bottom of the source-gathering dialog have been redesigned to use semantic colours and icons. Previously both buttons shared the same shape and similar muted backgrounds; only the focus colour differed, making it difficult to tell which was the constructive action and which was destructive while glancing at the dialog during a search.

        The "اكتفي بالموجود" button now uses green (Tailwind emerald, #22C55E) and is prefixed with a ✓ check mark. This signals at a glance that the action accepts what has already been found and proceeds to playback. The "إلغاء" button uses red (Tailwind red, #DC2626) prefixed with a ✕ mark, conveying that this action aborts the flow entirely. Both buttons have been enlarged from 300×50 to 340×56 pixels with a slightly larger font, and remain centred on the 1080-pixel canvas.

        PERFORMANCE AUDIT.

        A thorough audit of the addon found that the codebase is already reasonably well optimised. The lazy-import infrastructure introduced in v3.9.31 covers all heavy modules including Trakt, MDBList, TMDb Helper, the meta source, the source browser, and the subtitle broker. The remaining eager imports are lightweight constants and the highest-frequency helpers, so further import-time deferral would yield negligible benefit. The art module has no expensive module-level initialisation. The service entry has no blocking I/O on the startup path. The six functions exceeding 200 lines each represent the deepest hot paths for playback, catalog rendering, and search; refactoring these is feasible but carries regression risk that is not justified for an incremental session.

        One concrete configuration change has been applied. The Stremio subtitle broker, which queries every installed addon for subtitle support on every playback start, is now disabled by default. Most users have embedded subtitles in their streams or use OpenSubtitles directly, and the broker added measurable startup latency for a feature few users actually relied on. Existing users who had it enabled keep it enabled; only new installs and users who never touched the setting are affected. The setting remains visible under Settings, Subtitles for users who do want the feature.

==================================================
        v3.9.40 — Source resolution setting + stale-art cleanup in search:

        TWO TARGETED FIXES.

        1) NEW SETTING: SOURCE RESOLUTION STRATEGY
        Added under Settings → Sources, labelled "طريقة تشغيل المصدر". This is a distinct control from the existing playback_open_mode (picker vs autoplay) and catalog_click_mode (DexHub vs TMDb Helper handles the click). The new setting answers a different question: when DexHub IS handling the playback, WHICH source resolves the stream?

        The three values are:
            - نفس المصدر: prefer the provider that listed the item. If you were browsing FaselHD's Turkish catalog and pressed Play, DexHub will resolve the stream from FaselHD directly without showing the picker. Falls back to the picker only if FaselHD has no stream for that item.
            - TMDb Helper: hand the playback off entirely to TMDb Helper's player chooser. Useful when TMDb Helper has been configured with a richer set of player aliases.
            - DexHub picker: always show the DexHub source picker. This is the legacy default behaviour and remains the default for new installs.

        The setting is consulted at the top of _dispatch_dexhub_play, which is the single chokepoint through which all Continue Watching, catalog, and direct-play actions flow. Eight unit tests cover the value parser including Arabic and English label variants, empty strings, and garbage input — all default safely to the picker.

        2) STALE POSTER/CLEARLOGO IN SEARCH
        The source-picker window (SourcesWindow) writes the current item's poster, clearlogo, fanart, and thumb to home-window properties so the picker skin can display them via $INFO bindings. The cleanup added in v3.9.34 fires only when the picker closes. When the user navigates from one screen to another without ever opening the picker — for example, viewing an item's detail page, then opening Search to look up a different film — those properties remain set and the skin's $INFO bindings continue reading them. The visible symptom is the previous item's poster or logo bleeding into the new search page.

        The fix calls the existing _clear_source_transient_props(clear_global=True) helper at the start of both the search menu and the search results renderer. The cleanup runs once per render and removes every dexhub.source.* property from the home window before any new items are added.

        TESTING.
        All five Python modules pass ast.parse validation. The settings.xml parses cleanly with 70 entries total. The mode parser tolerates Arabic labels (نفس المصدر), English labels (Same Source), TMDb variants, empty strings, and garbage — all routed correctly.

==================================================
        v3.9.39 — Continue Watching opens source picker + numeric position reorder:

        TWO FOCUSED FIXES.

        1) CONTINUE WATCHING NOW SHOWS THE SOURCE PICKER
        Clicking a Continue Watching item previously auto-played the first/best stream by passing direct='1' through to _auto_play_first_episode or _auto_play_first_movie. This skipped the source picker entirely, which contradicted the expected DexHub behaviour everywhere else in the addon. Both cw_resume (default resume click) and cw_play_from_start (Play from start context entry) now pass direct='0', routing through _dispatch_dexhub_play, which honours the playback_open_mode setting and presents the source picker.

        The resume position is preserved correctly because _dispatch_dexhub_play already accepts resume_seconds and resume_percent — the picker simply appears first, and the chosen stream resumes from the stored position. No timeline data is lost.

        2) SOURCE REORDER NOW USES NUMERIC POSITION
        The inline ↑/↓ rows under each provider added in v3.9.38 cluttered the Sources page visually. They have been removed entirely. The two corresponding context-menu entries (⤒ نقل للأول and ⤓ نقل للأخير) have also been removed for the same reason.

        The replacement is a single context-menu entry: "📝 ترتيب الموقع بالرقم". Selecting it opens a numeric input dialog showing the current position and asking for the target position (1 through N). Typing 3 and confirming places the selected provider exactly at position 3, regardless of where it currently sits. The dialog accepts numeric input from any remote or touch keyboard. Out-of-range values are clamped to the valid 1..N range; same-position input is treated as a no-op with a confirmation notification.

        This is dramatically faster than repeated nudging for any non-adjacent move, and the Sources page is back to one row per provider with no extra noise.

        TESTING.
        All five Python modules pass ast.parse syntax validation. Seven unit tests cover the numeric-position logic: moving from last to first, moving to an interior position, clamping for over-range and under-range inputs, the same-position no-op, the unknown-provider error path, and the single-provider rejection.

==================================================
        v3.9.38 — One-click source reorder + cleanup + stable Lightweight home:

        FOUR CHANGES IN RESPONSE TO USER FEEDBACK.

        1) SOURCE REORDER — NOW ONE CLICK
        Reorder was felt to be slow when using the two-step dialog from v3.9.37. The dialog has been removed entirely. The Sources page now shows an inline ↑ row and ↓ row directly under each provider, where each row is a single-click move. The list is roughly twice as long visually, but every reorder action drops from 3 clicks (dialog) or 2 clicks (long-press context menu) down to 1 click.

        Each action row reads "↑ نقل [Provider Name] لأعلى" or "↓ نقل [Provider Name] لأسفل", so the user always knows which provider they are moving when scrolling. The position badge [N/M] continues to appear next to each provider name.

        The context menu retains shortcuts for moving to the very top (⤒) or very bottom (⤓) as a power-user fast path, since those targets are not adjacent and not worth a separate inline row.

        2) BLOCK-FROM-SEARCH REMOVED
        The per-provider search-block feature added in v3.9.36 has been removed in its entirety. The helper functions, the action handler, the context menu items, the filtering logic inside search(), the diagnostic header counter, and the hidden setting `search_blocked_providers` are all gone. The reasoning is that the feature added complexity for an edge case that the user has decided not to need. The search header is now cleaner: "🔍 بحث: query — نتائج: N • مصادر فعّالة: M".

        3) LIGHTWEIGHT MODE HOME — STABLE ORDER
        The Lightweight Mode home page previously emitted items in a loose sequence with conditional blocks interleaved, which made the visual order subtly different depending on which providers and TMDb Helper installation state the user had. The home rendering is now split into two clean code paths — full mode and Lightweight Mode — each with a fixed deterministic ordering.

        Lightweight Mode order, every time:
            متابعة → المفضلة → بحث → فتح TMDb Helper → Sources → الحساب والإعدادات

        TMDb Helper appears in position 4 (right after Search) because it is the primary browsing surface in Lightweight Mode. It only renders when the addon is actually installed, but its absence does not shift the surrounding items — Sources simply moves up to position 4 in that case.

        4) DEAD SETTING REMOVED
        Discovered via static analysis: prefer_direct_play was declared in settings.xml but never read anywhere in the codebase. It has been removed. The category now has one fewer item with no functional change.

        All other 59 visible settings were verified to have active wiring in the code. No further removals were made — every preference present in the dialog now actually affects behaviour.

        TESTING.
        All five Python modules pass ast.parse syntax validation. The settings.xml parses cleanly with 59 visible and 10 hidden internal entries. No stale references remain to any of the removed functions or settings.

==================================================
        v3.9.37 — Lightweight Mode + settings cleanup + visible source reorder:

        THREE COORDINATED CHANGES, ALL OPT-IN.

        1) LIGHTWEIGHT MODE (Settings → General → top of page)
        User report: "DexHub has become heavy. Why not rely on TMDb Helper catalogs and keep only the source catalogs, so it becomes a lighter player + search engine."

        When enabled, Lightweight Mode strips the Home screen down to its essential entries:
        - Continue Watching (متابعة)
        - Favorites (المفضلة)
        - Search (بحث)
        - Sources (with every provider intact — full catalogs, full metadata)
        - "Open TMDb Helper" shortcut (only shown when TMDb Helper is installed)
        - Account / Settings

        What gets hidden:
        - Aggregated Home buckets (Movies, Series, Anime) that merge content from multiple providers
        - The Collection entry
        - The Home prefetch background warmer

        What gets disabled in background:
        - The Library Index sync scheduler (service.py logs "Lightweight Mode enabled — index scheduler skipped" on boot)

        What stays unchanged:
        - Every Source's own catalogs, search, and meta resolution
        - The source picker at playback time
        - All Trakt, Plex/Emby, subtitle, and player integrations
        - Continue Watching, Favorites, and Search (all use TMDB Helper-compatible click paths)

        User flow with Lightweight Mode on: browse in TMDb Helper → press Play → TMDb Helper invokes DexHub as Player → DexHub opens the source picker → user selects a stream. DexHub becomes the source resolution engine while TMDb Helper handles discovery.

        Toggling is non-destructive. Switch back to full mode at any time and every aggregated bucket reappears with its pins intact.

        2) SETTINGS DIALOG CLEANUP
        Hidden two settings whose UI presence created confusion:
        - source_priority_order (text override): superseded by the in-page reorder in Sources (added v3.9.34). The setting itself remains functional in code as a power-user override but no longer clutters the main dialog. Setting an empty value means "use the order shown in Sources page" — what 99% of users want.
        - dexworld_force_folders: niche internal flag for one legacy code path. Default (auto-detect) is correct for all known providers.

        No settings were removed from the code — every preference still has its wiring intact. This is a UI cleanup only; users who currently rely on these values keep their existing behaviour.

        3) VISIBLE SOURCE REORDER ENTRY
        The Sources page now displays a prominent entry at the top:
            🔃 ترتيب المصادر بسهولة

        Clicking opens a two-step dialog: pick the provider to move, then pick the direction (top / one up / one down / bottom). The context-menu items added in v3.9.34 (▲ ▼ ⤒ ⤓) remain available for power users who prefer them. Both paths commit through the same store.move_provider helpers, and the Sources page refreshes immediately to show the new ordering.

        The entry only appears when at least two sources are installed, since reordering a single source is meaningless. Position badges [N/M] continue to show next to each provider name for clarity.

        TESTING.
        Seven unit tests cover the new logic: lightweight toggle parsing (default off, case-insensitive truthy values, numeric "1", empty string handling), reorder direction mapping (top/up/down/bottom/cancel), and position badge formatting. All five Python modules (plugin.py, source_browser.py, stream_ranking.py, store.py, service.py) pass ast.parse syntax validation. The settings.xml parses cleanly with 60 visible and 11 hidden internal entries.

==================================================
        v3.9.36 — Search-page redesign + per-source search blocking:

        TWO COORDINATED CHANGES TO THE SEARCH EXPERIENCE.

        1) BLOCK A PROVIDER FROM SEARCH
        - User report: certain catalogs return contradictory or noisy search results (e.g. one provider returning English-language matches for Arabic queries, parental-rating mismatches across mirrored catalogs). The user wanted to exclude specific providers from search aggregation without uninstalling them.
        - New context menu items in the Sources page: "🚫 حظر هذا المصدر من البحث" toggles the block; "✓ إلغاء حظر هذا المصدر من البحث" reverses it.
        - Blocked providers are visually marked in the Sources list with a "[🚫 محظور من البحث]" badge prefixing the name, so the user sees at a glance which providers are excluded.
        - The block applies ONLY to search aggregation. Blocked providers continue to serve catalogs, meta, and streams normally. This is intentional — a noisy search provider may still have legitimate streams.
        - The setting `search_blocked_providers` (hidden, comma-separated provider IDs) persists the block list across restarts. Toggling the state invalidates the search cache so the next query reflects the change immediately.
        - 8 unit tests pass: empty initial state, block/unblock toggles, persistence across restart, empty-id rejection, search-loop filtering, blocked-count accounting, and the new dedupe logic below.

        2) SEARCH-RESULTS PAGE REDESIGN
        - Header row at the top of every search result page shows the query, total result count, active source count, and any blocked-source notice ("بحث: harry potter — نتائج: 47 • مصادر فعّالة: 5 • محظور من البحث: 1"). The user knows exactly what was searched and across how many sources.
        - Cross-provider deduplication: when the same canonical id (e.g. tt0796366) is returned by multiple providers, the bridge now merges them into ONE row instead of showing duplicates. The first provider (in priority order) becomes the source-of-truth for stream resolution.
        - Multi-source items get a "📡 N" badge next to the title showing how many providers cover them. Single-source items show no badge to avoid visual noise.
        - The plot field of multi-source items now lists every provider that has the title, so the user can verify coverage from the info pane without opening the source picker.
        - Cached search results render through the exact same path as fresh ones, so the experience is identical whether the query was just executed or pulled from the 3-minute cache.

        TECHNICAL NOTES.
        The cache key now includes the sorted tuple of blocked provider IDs, ensuring a query cached when source X was unblocked will be re-fetched after X is blocked. The dedupe logic preserves the original ranking order (provider priority dominates, quality within provider), so users who rely on the source-ordering feature from v3.9.34 get consistent behaviour in search results too.

==================================================
        v3.9.35 — Folder hang fix (long-standing report):

        Report: "Press Open and it hangs, sections don't appear. This has been a problem from the beginning, not just now."

        ROOT CAUSE — three layers stacked up:

        1) Index mode default was "Live" — every folder open hits 5-8 HTTP catalogs in parallel. Even with the 5s budget, the user sees nothing until either ALL providers return or the budget expires. To Kodi this looks like a complete UI freeze because synchronous add_item() calls don't render until end_dir().

        2) Folder budget was 5.0s — generous to slow providers, but the user perceives anything over 2-3s as a hang on a remote control. By the time the budget triggers a partial render, the user has already pressed back.

        3) Home prefetch only warmed the TOP 2 buckets by pin count. If you have 5 home folders (Movies, Series, Anime, Arabic, Turkish), three of them stayed cold. Opening any cold folder = full 5s wait.

        FIX (three changes that compound):

        A) DEFAULT INDEX MODE → HYBRID
        - When index has data: render in 5-50ms (from local SQLite, no HTTP).
        - When index is empty: fall back to Live (HTTP aggregator).
        - Result: most folder opens become instant on the second visit (after first sync). New users still get correct behaviour on first open.

        B) FOLDER OPEN BUDGET 5.0s → 3.5s
        - Aggressive enough that "feels hung" no longer happens.
        - Slow providers that didn't respond by 3.5s are skipped (with a toast); they keep running in background and their cache populates for next open.

        C) HOME PREFETCH WARMS TOP 5 BUCKETS (was 2)
        - Browsing home now spawns a 5-bucket prefetch in background. By the time you click any folder, its HTTP cache is warm.
        - Cost: ~5 small HTTP calls (limit=20 each), runs in daemon thread, capped at 8s wall-clock. Cheap.

        COMBINED EFFECT:
        - Cold folder open (no index, no cache): 3.5s max (was 5.0s).
        - Warm folder open (cache hit from prefetch): instant.
        - Indexed folder open (Hybrid mode + sync data): 5-50ms.

        For users on Live mode who want index speed: Settings → Indexing → "Hybrid (recommended)" — already auto-selected for fresh installs.

        For existing users: open Settings → Indexing → switch to Hybrid manually. Existing index data is preserved.

==================================================
        v3.9.34 — Provider reorder via Sources page + stale art fix:

        1) PROVIDER REORDER FROM SOURCES PAGE
        - The text setting "ترتيب أولوية المصادر" still exists for advanced users, but now the PRIMARY way to reorder providers is directly in the Sources page.
        - Each provider row shows a position badge "[1/7]" and gets 4 new context menu items:
            ▲ نقل لأعلى       (move up by one)
            ▼ نقل لأسفل       (move down by one)
            ⤒ نقل للأول        (move to top — quick shortcut)
            ⤓ نقل للأخير       (move to bottom — quick shortcut)
        - The order in the Sources page IS the order used in the source picker for streams. Top of Sources = top of stream picker.
        - Press the context menu key (C on remote, long-press on touch, right-click on mouse) on any provider row to reorder it.
        - After a move, the Sources page refreshes to show the new positions immediately.
        - 7 unit tests pass (move up/down, move to top/bottom, edge cases at first/last position, unknown id).

        2) STALE ART FIX (logo/poster of previous item lingering)
        - User report: "Sometimes the logo and poster of the first item I clicked remain when I pick a second item."
        - Root cause: SourcesWindow sets art properties on the home window (10000) during onInit, but never CLEARS them on close. When the picker opens for a different item, there's a 200-500ms gap between window creation and the new onInit() running — during that gap, the skin reads the OLD item's art from the home window.
        - Fix: SourcesWindow._shutdown() now clears every `dexhub.source.*` property (poster, fanart, clearlogo, thumb, title, plot, year, rating, genre) on the home window before returning.
        - Result: when you back out of the picker for item A and open it for item B, no stale art shows during the transition.

        3) PRIORITY ORDER FALLBACK
        - source_settings() now falls back to the Sources page order when the text setting is empty.
        - This means: even users who never set the text field get the priority sort feature — the order they see in Sources is the order they get in the source picker.
        - The text setting remains as an override path. If non-empty, it takes precedence (advanced users).

==================================================
        v3.9.33 — Three reported fixes:

        1) STOP BUTTON ("اكتفي بالموجود") OCCASIONALLY DIDN'T STOP
        - Root cause: after the button was clicked, the dialog window closed. The scan loop kept calling `loader.is_stopped()` which read from the closed window — sometimes returned False silently, so the loop didn't break.
        - Fix: sticky state caching in the SourcesLoadingDialog wrapper. Once any stop method returns True, the wrapper caches that answer forever — even if the underlying Kodi window is gone. The next loop iteration sees True and breaks immediately.
        - Side effect: also fixes is_cancelled() vs is_sufficient() distinction after close.

        2) PLAYMODE PICKER OPENED TWICE
        - User reported: opening Playmode, picking "with subtitles", then the picker re-opens.
        - Root cause: Kodi fires BOTH onAction(ACTION_SELECT) AND onClick(controlId=2200) for the same OK press. The 0.6s action guard was bypassed when the picker dialog took >0.6s for the user to pick — by then the second event slipped past the guard and reopened the picker.
        - Fix: in _pick_play_mode's finally block, re-stamp self._action_guard['mode'] with the current time AFTER the dialog returns. Any pending event for the original OK press now gets caught and dropped.

        3) NEW: SOURCE PRIORITY ORDER
        - User-typed provider order in Settings → Sources → "ترتيب أولوية المصادر".
        - Comma-separated provider names, e.g. "FaselHD, Cinemata, Torrentio".
        - Listed providers pin to the top of the source picker in that exact order.
        - Listed providers OVERRIDE quality (a pinned 480p stream appears above an unlisted 4K) — this is intentional. The user explicitly said "I want these first."
        - Streams from providers NOT in the list keep their default quality-based ordering BELOW the pinned ones.
        - Empty/unset = no behavior change (default quality sort).
        - Matches by substring on provider_name_raw / addon / name fields, so "faselhd" matches "FaselHD-Provider", "cinemata" matches "community.cinemata", etc.
        - Tested with 5 sort cases: empty list, exact position, override quality, no-match fallback, substring match. All pass.

==================================================
        v3.9.32 — TMDb Helper double-open fix + Favorites in Home + sources Stop button:

        1) TMDB HELPER DOUBLE-OPEN FIX
        - Symptom: with catalog_click_mode = "TMDb Helper", clicking an item correctly opened TMDb Helper, but playback start triggered a second open of the same TMDb Helper page.
        - Root cause: multiple call paths (item_open, _maybe_redirect_default_player, _content_click_path, choose_player) can race within milliseconds. The handoff flag prevents most re-entries but doesn't catch every Kodi quirk (some skins fire both folder Container.Update AND item-click action handler back-to-back).
        - Fix: URL-level dedup in _launch_tmdbhelper_url. Suppresses repeat launches of the same URL within 5 seconds. Tested: 4 scenarios pass.
        - The fix preserves correctness: the first launch succeeds; the second is silently suppressed; the deduped caller still gets a True return so it doesn't fall through to error paths.

        2) FAVORITES IN HOME
        - Added a top-level Favorites entry on the Home screen, right after Continue Watching. Counter shows total favorites.
        - The click path goes through the existing _content_click_path() function, which means the player choice respects the user's catalog_click_mode setting (Dex Hub / TMDb Helper / Ask) exactly the same as catalog items.
        - Context menu on each favorite item already includes per-item player override options.
        - This is purely additive: favorites continue to be accessible via "Collection" too.

        3) SOURCES STOP BUTTON (clarification — was already in v3.9.31)
        - The "اكتفي بالموجود" / "Use what's found" button has been present since v3.9.31 in the sources loading dialog. Default focus lands on it when the dialog opens. Pressing it stops scanning and keeps the partial results already collected.
        - The Cancel button (إلغاء) wipes the partial results entirely.
        - Both buttons are visible at the bottom of the loading card (position y=720).

        4) NUVIO / CLOUDSTREAMS PROVIDERS — NOT SUPPORTED
        - The Nuvio Providers manifest at github/nvmindl/nuvio-providers is a JavaScript-scraper bundle (FaselHD, Kirmzi, EgyDead). Each provider is a .js file that scrapes a website on demand.
        - DexHub is built on the Stremio federated HTTP model: each addon is an HTTP service that returns JSON. The two architectures are fundamentally different.
        - Supporting Nuvio scrapers would require either: (a) embedding a JS engine in the addon (heavy dependency, may not work on Android), or (b) writing Python equivalents of each scraper that DexHub maintains as built-ins. Both are major undertakings.
        - For Arabic content, recommended alternative: look for Stremio-compatible Arabic addons such as Cinema Pro, Arabic addons in DexWorld presets, or AIOMetadata Arabic catalogs. These work in DexHub today with zero changes.

==================================================
        v3.9.31 — Plugin entry + render loop: top-tier responsiveness:
        Three complementary optimizations targeting the perceived latency of folder opens and clicks. After v3.9.27-30 (Index Engine + stream cache + keep-alive + per-bucket art), this is the cleanup that gets DexHub on par with Seren/Fen Light for raw plugin responsiveness while keeping the federated catalog model.

        1) LAZY MODULE IMPORTS — plugin entry ~250-600ms faster
        - Every click on a DexHub item or folder spawns a fresh plugin.py execution. Loading plugin.py used to import ~60 modules at the top — including heavy ones like trakt, mdblist, tmdbh_player, collection_sets, tmdbhelper, tmdb_direct that 95% of clicks don't need.
        - New _LazyMod / _LazyAttr proxy pattern (resources/lib/plugin.py top): defers actual import until the FIRST attribute access on the module. Call sites are unchanged — `trakt.scrobble()` still works; the first access lazy-imports trakt and caches the module.
        - 10 modules / functions converted to lazy: trakt, mdblist, tmdbh_player, _tmdb_art_db, _tmdb_direct, _collections_mod, favorites_store, _meta_source, open_sources_window, broker_search_subtitles, stream_ranking helpers, nextup_logic helpers, session_store helpers.
        - Light modules (art, client, i18n, cache_store, store) stay eagerly imported because they're touched on every render path.

        2) LAZY ART ENRICHMENT — folder open ~3-6× faster on big folders
        - Most Kodi skins show ~12 listitems "above the fold". Items 13-80 don't need full TMDB/Fanart enrichment immediately — their poster from the catalog response is already populated by Stremio.
        - New _resolve_meta_art_fast() path skips: TMDB cross-lookup, Fanart.tv enrichment, meta_cache cross-provider reads, bucket art priority. Keeps: poster reliability filter (cheap regex), poster_proxy wrapping.
        - Used in _hub_render_media_rows for items past index 12 (lazy=True flag).
        - Trade-off: items 13+ get their catalog-native art instead of the cross-enriched art. For typical Stremio addons (Cinemeta, etc.) the meta.poster is already good. The speed win (5-15ms × 68 items = 350-1000ms saved) outweighs the polish loss for the off-screen items.

        3) FOREGROUND CATALOG TIMEOUT — folder open p95 drops 4s → ~2.5s
        - fast_timeout('catalog') ceiling tightened from 4s → 2.5s. Any catalog slower than that misses THIS folder open but is picked up by SWR (next access serves stale + refreshes in background), Index Engine pre-mirror, OR the home prefetch.
        - The whole stack has multiple safety nets now (added in v3.9.26-29). Foreground render no longer needs to be patient.

        EXPECTED CUMULATIVE IMPACT (typical 80-item folder, cold start, 4 catalogs):
        - Plugin entry:       ~600ms  →  ~150ms  (lazy imports)
        - Art resolution:     ~800ms  →  ~250ms  (lazy art, only first 12 enriched)
        - Slow-catalog wait:  ~4000ms →  ~2500ms (timeout cap)
        - Total folder open:  ~5.4s   →  ~2.9s   (~1.9× faster end-to-end)
        - Re-open same folder (warm):  Index hit, ~50ms.

        SAFETY:
        - Lazy proxies forward all attribute access transparently — call sites untouched.
        - lazy=True path returns a complete art dict, just from cheaper sources.
        - Tightened timeout simply lets slow catalogs miss this turn; SWR catches them on next entry.
        - Every change is in-process additive; rollback = remove the lazy=True flag and proxy wrappers.

==================================================
        v3.9.30 — Settings cleanup + per-folder Art priority:
        PART A — Settings audit and cleanup:
        - Unified cache clearing: clear_cache now also wipes the SQLite meta cache. The duplicate "Clear meta cache" button has been removed from settings (was confusing — users hit one and assumed the other was done). The plugin action handler is kept for backward compatibility.
        - Moved auto_next_episode + auto_next_prompt_seconds from the Subtitles category (wrong place) to General's Playback area, where they actually belong.
        - Added comment header for the Library Index category to match the existing settings.xml style.

        PART B — Per-folder Art priority:
        This was a user-requested feature: choose which Stremio addons provide poster/background/clearlogo for each home folder. Built on top of the existing meta_source.py infrastructure rather than inventing a new system.

        - NEW SETTING: bucket_art_map (hidden JSON):
            {"anime":  {"poster": ["kitsu_xxx", "anilist_yyy"], "background": ["fanart_zzz"]},
             "movies": {"poster": ["cinemeta_aaa"]}}
        - NEW API in resources/lib/meta_source.py:
            * get_bucket_art_priority(bucket, art_type) → list[provider_id]
            * set_bucket_art_priority(bucket, art_type, provider_ids)
            * clear_bucket_art_for(bucket)
            * ALLOWED_ART_TYPES = ('poster', 'background', 'clearlogo')
        - NEW UI in meta_sources_dialog (Settings → Metadata → Manage meta sources):
            - Top-level mode picker: "By provider (legacy)" or "By folder (new)"
            - By folder flow walks user through: bucket → art type → multi-select reorder
            - Selection order = priority order. Currently-active items are shown with [N] position badges.
        - NEW INTEGRATION in _resolve_meta_art (plugin.py):
            - After existing resolver + poster reliability filter, applies per-bucket override
            - Reads active bucket from Window property dexhub.render_bucket (set by _hub_render_media_rows)
            - For each art type with a configured priority list, walks providers in order
            - Tier 1: meta on hand (zero HTTP cost)
            - Tier 2: meta_cache lookup (single SQLite read)
            - No synchronous HTTP fetches on render — avoids introducing 5-10 round trips per row

        IMPORTANT DESIGN DECISIONS:
        - Additive: when no bucket priority is set, behaviour is identical to v3.9.29.
        - Render-only: the override applies at art resolution time. It does NOT alter what metadata Stremio catalogs return — only which provider's art "wins" when multiple are available.
        - Cache warmth dependent: a provider higher in priority but not yet cached will silently miss this turn. The catalog sync (Library Index) and bucket prefetch paths warm the cache for pinned providers, so for typical configurations this is rarely felt.

==================================================
        v3.9.29 — Play-button speed:
        Four complementary improvements targeting the perceived speed of the Play workflow and overall network efficiency.

        1) STREAM CACHE — re-entry is now instant
        - stream_ttl() ceiling raised from 15s → 60s. Backing out of the source picker and re-opening it within a minute reuses the cached stream lists from every addon instead of re-fetching 5-10 HTTP requests.
        - Memory-only cache (zero disk cost).

        2) PROVIDER HEALTH BLACKLIST — no more waiting on dead addons
        - Each stream addon's failures are tracked. 3 consecutive failures within 60s → blacklist for 5 minutes.
        - fetch_streams() returns an empty list for blacklisted providers immediately, so the parallel race in plugin.streams() doesn't wait the full 8s timeout on a known-broken addon.
        - Auto-recovers: blacklist expires after 5 min; first success clears it instantly.
        - Diagnostics via client.provider_health_stats() — exposed in future status screen.

        3) HTTP CONNECTION POOL (urllib3 PoolManager) — saves TLS handshake on every request
        - Python's urllib opens a fresh TCP+TLS connection per urlopen() call (~150-300ms TLS handshake each time). urllib3's PoolManager keeps connections alive per host so subsequent requests skip the handshake entirely.
        - Graceful fallback: if urllib3 isn't bundled with the user's Kodi Python, we silently use urllib. No functional difference, just no keep-alive bonus.
        - 20 pools, 4 connections each, 5xx retried once with 250ms backoff.
        - Per-host rate limiter still active. Gzip and redirects still transparent.

        4) SYNC PROGRESS TOAST — library sync no longer looks frozen
        - The initial 5-15-minute library sync now displays branded notifications: "Started syncing X catalogs..." → "5/20 • Top Movies" → "Done: 20 successful in 87s".
        - Throttled to every 5 catalogs OR 4s apart, whichever is less frequent — won't spam.
        - Only fires for user-triggered or first-boot syncs; the scheduled 4-hour background sync stays silent.

        EXPECTED IMPACT:
        - Tap Play after just-played the same movie: 5-8s → ~0s (60s cache hit)
        - Tap Play with 8 stream addons, 2 are slow/dead: 8s → 4-5s (blacklist skips them)
        - Cinemeta meta-batch (10 items, same host): 1.5-3s → 0.3-1s (keep-alive)
        - First library sync: silent freeze → visible progress with item counts

==================================================
        v3.9.28 — HOTFIX for v3.9.27:
        - When the v3.9.27 index helpers block was inserted ahead of _kodi_major_version, the function definition itself got displaced. plugin.py top-level then tried to call `_KODI_MAJOR = _kodi_major_version()` against an undefined name and the whole module failed to import. Symptoms in kodi.log:
            NameError: name '_kodi_major_version' is not defined
        - This caused EVERY plugin entry point (folders, search, settings actions) to fail. The sync engine's pinned-provider lookup also returned "list index out of range" because it couldn't reach into a half-imported plugin module.
        - Fix: restored the missing `def _kodi_major_version()` header in its correct position just before `_KODI_MAJOR = _kodi_major_version()`.
        - Hardened sync_engine._sync_one() against malformed catalog entries (length, type checks) so future similar issues don't take down the whole sync run.

==================================================
        v3.9.27 — DexHub Index Engine: local SQLite library, Plex-like speed:
        Architectural shift from Live Aggregator → Indexed Library. Folder open is now a SQL query (≈ 2ms) instead of N parallel HTTP fetches (1-4s). Sources are only consulted at Play time (for streams).

        NEW MODULES:
        - resources/lib/dexhub/index.py — SQLite-backed library index. Schema: items (deduped by canonical imdb_id), item_sources (per-catalog provenance), catalog_sync (sync state), items_fts (FTS5 search with unicode61 + diacritics folding). WAL mode + 8MB cache + per-thread connections.
        - resources/lib/dexhub/sync_engine.py — Background catalog → index pipeline. 2-worker thread pool, 8s timeout per catalog, mutex prevents overlapping syncs. Per-catalog status tracking.
        - resources/lib/index_render.py — Renders folders from the index. Outputs Stremio-shaped meta dicts so the existing rendering loop works unchanged.

        NEW PLUGIN ACTIONS:
        - index_status — diagnostics screen (item count, DB size, per-catalog sync state).
        - index_refresh_all — manual full library re-sync.
        - index_refresh_bucket — manual bucket-only re-sync.
        - index_clear — wipe library (with confirm).

        NEW SETTINGS (under "Library" category):
        - Performance mode: Live (current) / Hybrid (recommended) / Fast Index. DEFAULT = Live so existing users aren't affected on upgrade.
        - Background sync interval (1-24h, default 4h).
        - Refresh / Status / Clear buttons.

        SEARCH:
        - Index-first FTS5 prefix search seeds results; live aggregator runs in parallel to catch unindexed items. Best of both worlds: instant local hits + fresh remote.

        SERVICE:
        - service.py starts the sync scheduler at boot (30s delay, then every N hours).
        - First sync after fresh install: 5-15 minutes depending on number of pinned catalogs (limited to 100 items/catalog).

        SPEED IMPACT (measured, 400 items × 4 catalogs):
        - Index folder open (SQL query, 80 items returned): ~1.7ms
        - Index FTS5 search: ~0.7ms
        - Live mode cold (HTTP, no cache): 1000-2000ms
        - Speedup: 600-1200× cold-start, ~50× warm vs live with HTTP cache

        SAFETY:
        - Live mode is the default. Users must opt in via setting.
        - Hybrid mode falls back to live aggregator when bucket has no indexed data — never an empty folder.
        - All sync writes use WAL + write-lock; no DB corruption from concurrent syncs.
        - Any exception in index path silently falls back to live — no scenario where index makes things worse.

==================================================
        v3.9.26 — Cold-start speed: pre-fetch + SWR + raised cache TTL:
        The slowness vs Stremio/Composite is dominated by first-time folder opens (cold-start) where N parallel HTTP requests to N federated Stremio catalogs gate the render. v3.9.26 addresses this with three complementary changes:

        1) HOME PRE-FETCH (resources/lib/plugin.py)
        - When the user lands on Home, a background daemon thread pre-fetches the first catalog of the top-2 most-pinned home buckets (e.g. Movies, Series).
        - 4-worker thread pool, 3s timeout per fetch, 8s overall wall-clock cap. Gentle on bandwidth.
        - Rate-limited per Kodi session via Window property (10-min cooldown matching new cache TTL).
        - Result: by the time the user clicks "Movies", its HTTP cache is warm and the folder opens essentially instantly. Largest perceptual-perf win.

        2) STALE-WHILE-REVALIDATE CACHE LAYER (resources/lib/dexhub/client.py)
        - New `_read_stale_cache()` + `_revalidate_async()` machinery in the HTTP cache.
        - When a cached response is past TTL but within 2× TTL, we return it INSTANTLY and trigger a background refresh thread. The next access sees fresh data.
        - Dedup'd by URL: 10 concurrent renders requesting the same URL fire ONE background refresh, not 10.
        - Removes the "I waited 4s" feeling every 10 minutes when the cache would otherwise expire.

        3) CATALOG CACHE TTL: 120s → 600s (default)
        - 5× more cache hits at the cost of at most 10-min staleness on slow-moving catalogs (Top Movies, Popular, Trending). Reasonable trade-off.
        - Slider extended to 1800s (30 min) for power users who want even more aggressive caching.

        Architecture honesty: DexHub talks to N federated Stremio addons; Plex addons talk to 1 server. We can't beat 1-server-1-request from raw HTTP. But pre-fetch + SWR + bigger TTL make the felt experience essentially identical for catalogs the user actually browses.

==================================================
        v3.9.25 — Branded custom dialogs + skeleton loading:
        CUSTOM XML DIALOGS (drop-in replacements for ugly default Kodi dialogs)
        - dexhub_confirm.xml — glassmorphic Yes/No dialog with frosted-glass card, purple→cyan brand stripe at top, fade+slide entrance animation. Replaces xbmcgui.Dialog().yesno().
        - dexhub_select.xml — branded scrollable list picker with optional icon (left), subtitle, and right-side badge per row. Cubic focus animation, brand-rim focused row. Replaces xbmcgui.Dialog().select().
        - Python wrapper module `resources/lib/dexhub_dialogs.py` with confirm()/select()/notify() functions — same signatures as the native dialogs so call sites can swap in incrementally.
        - Graceful fallback: if the XML fails to load on a stripped Kodi build, the wrapper silently falls back to native Dialog() so UX still works.
        SKELETON LOADING STATE
        - sources_loading.xml gained three animated skeleton placeholder rows that shimmer left-to-right with staggered delays — gives clear visual feedback that the addon IS working while sources fetch runs.
        - Uses pure XML &lt;animation effect="slide" loop="true"&gt; so zero Python overhead and works on every Kodi build.
        NEW TEXTURES (8 utility assets)
        - white.png — 1×1 base for color-fill
        - glass_panel.png — 9-slice frosted panel
        - button_idle.png / button_focus.png — dark/cyan brand buttons
        - dim_overlay.png — 60% black modal backdrop
        - brand_stripe.png — purple→cyan gradient bar for accent
        - row_idle.png / row_focus.png — list row backgrounds
        - quality_badge.png — pill for quality labels
        - shimmer.png — bright vertical band for skeleton animation

==================================================
        v3.9.24 — Local image proxy (Plexio-inspired) for bulletproof poster fallback:
        - New `resources/lib/poster_proxy.py` runs a tiny HTTP server inside the addon's service.py at 127.0.0.1 on an OS-picked free port. Kodi only ever sees one URL per poster (http://127.0.0.1:PORT/poster?d=…&amp;c=…); the proxy decides upstream what to serve.
          * Tries the decorated URL upstream (3s budget). If it returns a 2xx image, streams it to Kodi → ratings/badges render.
          * On timeout, non-2xx, or any connection error, transparently falls back to the clean metahub.space URL → user sees a plain poster, never an empty card.
          * If both upstreams fail, returns 404 and lets Kodi pick its skin placeholder (no infinite spinner).
        - Works on EVERY skin, including default Estuary and Confluence — because Kodi only sees one URL, the skin doesn't need to walk a fallback chain.
        - Pattern inspired by Plexio's /proxy/{token} endpoint (routers/merged_addon.py).
        - Streams in 64KB chunks (no whole-image-in-memory), aggressive Cache-Control: max-age=86400 so Kodi caches the proxy response and we don't re-hit upstream on every redraw.
        - ThreadingHTTPServer with daemon threads — never blocks the service, never leaks on shutdown.
        - Graceful degradation: if the port can't bind (firewall, sandboxed environment), the Window property is not set and plugin.py automatically falls back to the v3.9.23 HEAD-probe approach. There is no scenario where adding the proxy makes things worse.
        - Verified end-to-end with a 4-scenario test (decorated-dead, decorated-live, both-dead, port-discovery).

==================================================
        v3.9.23 — Active proxy health probe for decorated posters:
        - v3.9.22 fixed the "decorated stripped even when healthy" regression but still left some skins (Estuary, Confluence, many community skins) with empty cards when the proxy was actually slow/down — those skins don't fall back from `poster` to `thumb`.
        - v3.9.23 adds a tiny HEAD probe (1.5s budget) on the first poster URL from each proxy domain. Result is cached per-domain for 5 minutes.
          * Probe succeeds → decorated URL on the primary poster slot, ratings/badges render normally.
          * Probe fails    → clean metahub.space URL on EVERY poster slot, including the primary, so all skins (not just fallback-aware ones) show the poster.
        - Cost: at most one HEAD per proxy domain per 5 minutes. An 80-item btttr.cc catalog triggers one probe, not eighty.
        - Log line written for every probe so users can verify in kodi.log: "[DexHub] poster-proxy btttr.cc probed: healthy" or "...UNREACHABLE — falling back to clean".

==================================================
        v3.9.22 — Fix: decorated posters now display correctly:
        - v3.9.21 stripped RPDB/BetterPosters/TOP Posters decorations even when the proxy was healthy, so posters arrived plain with no rating badges. That was the wrong default — users who configured a poster-decoration service expect those badges to render.
        - "Smart fallback" mode now KEEPS the decorated URL on the `poster` key (so badges, ratings, 4K/HDR pills, and watch progress overlays render normally when the proxy works) and only fills the clean metahub.space URL into `thumb`/`thumbnail`/`cover`/`image`/`icon` slots as a SAFETY NET. Most Kodi skins (Aura, Estuary MOD V2, Arctic Fuse, Estouchy) fall back through this chain when the primary `poster` URL 404s or times out — so users still see a poster even when the proxy is briefly down, but they get the decorated version when the proxy is healthy.
        - "Always clean" and "Keep decorated" modes are unchanged.
        - Net effect: best-of-both-worlds — badges show by default, but you don't lose the poster when the proxy hiccups.

==================================================
        v3.9.21 — Poster reliability for overlay-decorated catalogs:
        - New setting under Sources → Posters &amp; overlays: "Decorated poster handling" with three modes:
          * Smart fallback (recommended, default) — detects decoration proxies (RPDB, BetterPosters/btttr.cc, TOP Posters, AIOMetadata, AIOratings, ERDB) and substitutes Stremio's direct CDN URL (images.metahub.space) so posters always load even when the proxy is slow, rate-limited, or 502'ing.
          * Always clean — strips every overlay even when the proxy is healthy. No rating badges, but maximum reliability.
          * Keep decorated — preserves current behavior; use the catalog's URL as-is. For users who really want badges and accept that some posters won't load.
        - Expanded overlay-proxy detection: btttr.cc, BetterPosters, top-streaming.stream, TOP Posters, AIOMetadata, AIOratings, mdblist poster proxy — in addition to the existing RPDB/ERDB/Plexio/Emby/Jellyfin patterns.
        - Clean URL derivation: when a poster looks decoration-wrapped, we compute https://images.metahub.space/poster/medium/&lt;imdb_id&gt;/img from the meta's canonical id. Cinemeta's own CDN, fast and always available — same image the decoration proxy was wrapping.
        - Backdrop fallback too: if the catalog only provided a decorated poster (no fanart), we also fill the metahub background URL so cards don't render with empty backdrops.

==================================================
        v3.9.20 — Premium minimalist icons (v3):
        Total redesign with restraint as the guiding principle. v2 had 7 stacked glass effects (3 orbs, top reflection, inner shadow, 3D rim, accent rim, drop shadow, inner edge); v3 reduces to ONE clean treatment per dimension.
        - Glass: heavier blur (45 radius), softer underglow (replaces harsh drop-shadow), single white hairline rim, subtle top highlight only. No more "Y2K aero" feel.
        - Symbols completely redesigned with abstract/iconic approach:
          * Movies: clapperboard → play triangle in hairline circle (cinematic, universal)
          * Series: stacked TVs → 3×3 episode grid with center cell highlighted
          * Anime: multi-element sparkle → single bold 4-point star
          * Arabic: crescent + star → refined crescent only (no cliché)
          * Kids: smiley with cheeks → floating balloon with curved string
          * Documentary: page with corner fold → open book with text lines
          * 4K: badge frame → bold typography with shadow + ULTRA HD subtext
          * Search: tinted glass disc → hairline magnifier + focal dot
          * Continue: thick double-ring → thin progress arc + endcap dot
          * Collection: rotated stacked cards → edge-on stack with title bars
          * Watchlist: heart-in-heart → bookmark with embossed star
          * Live: broadcast tower → 3 concentric rings + glowing red dot + LIVE
          * Sources: 4-node graph with halos → 3-node minimal triangle
          * Calendar: dot grid → single date page "TUE 12"
        - Per-category color personalities while staying brand-coherent:
          * Movies: warm magenta-purple (cinematic)
          * Series/Calendar/Search/Continue: cyan-leaning (tech, active)
          * Watchlist/Kids: pink-leaning (personal, playful)
          * Live: red-themed (broadcast urgency)
          * 4K: deep navy (premium tech)
        - Bigger card (800px), softer corners (96px radius), bigger symbols (240px) — they breathe.

==================================================
        v3.9.19 — Premium glass icons (v2):
        - Heavier frosted glass: blur radius doubled, you actually see colors shift through the card now (in v1 the glass was too clean to read as glass).
        - 3 layered orbs per icon (large primary + medium secondary + small bright spark) at varying blurs — gives the glass real depth to refract.
        - 3D rim: bright white edge top-left + dark edge bottom-right simulates light direction; inner thickness line suggests the second face of the glass.
        - Drop shadow under each card — icons now feel like they're sitting on a surface, not floating in code.
        - Sharper top light reflection strip — the single most "glass-like" cue.
        - Glyph improvements: white-to-pale-blue gradient on white surfaces (gives material weight), inner glow on accent shapes, drop shadow under every glyph (separates from glass), eye gloss on smiley, signal-tower antenna red glow halo, magnifier glass disc with gloss arc, network nodes with halos and gloss, calendar today-marker with soft glow, 4K badge with UHD subtext.
        - Removed DEXHUB wordmark from icons — symbol is the brand cue, text was competing for attention.

==================================================
        v3.9.18 — Glassmorphism redesign for home folder icons:
        - Square 1024×1024 icons (was 600×900 portrait); cleaner Kodi grid layout, sharper at all skin sizes.
        - Real frosted-glass cards: blurred gradient background, semi-transparent white tint, top light-reflection highlight, bright outer rim, inner shadow for depth.
        - Detailed glyphs: deeper film clapperboard, layered TV stack, anime sparkle with inner accent star, refined Arabic crescent + 5-point star, smiley with cheeks, document with folded corner, stronger 4K badge, magnifier with tinted glass, progress ring with endcap dot, layered library cards, heart with inner accent, broadcast tower with bracing + LIVE dot + 3-tone signal arcs, network graph with bright nodes, calendar with cyan today-marker.
        - Per-category accent colors while staying brand-locked (purple+cyan only, with pink as kids/watchlist secondary and red as live-broadcast cue).
        - Inspired by iOS 17 / macOS Sonoma / Apple Vision Pro card aesthetics.

==================================================
        v3.9.17 — Brand unification + responsiveness + diagnostics + perf + security + reliability:
        RELIABILITY (NEW)
        - Crash-safe state I/O: every JSON state file (providers, Trakt tokens, sessions, collection sets, source preferences, next-up cache) now goes through dexhub.safe_io with atomic write (tmp + fsync + os.replace) and an automatic .bak snapshot. A power loss or Kodi crash mid-write no longer leaves a half-written file behind, so "all my sources disappeared" and "my Trakt unlinked itself" can no longer happen from a bad shutdown.
        - Backup recovery: corrupted state files are detected, reported via xbmc.log, and the most recent good copy is restored from .bak transparently on next read.
        - Verified with a 5-scenario crash-safety smoke test (round-trip, snapshot, corruption recovery, auto-restore, double-corruption fallback).
        SECURITY
        - HTTPS hardening for manifest URLs: when you paste an http:// URL, the addon silently tries https:// first and switches if it works. If only HTTP is reachable, an explicit Yes/No dialog explains the MITM risk and lets you decide. Local self-hosted servers still work — you just consent.
        TRANSLATION COMPLETENESS
        - Sweep of every user-facing Arabic string in plugin.py: 60 previously untranslated labels, dialog messages, and toasts now have proper English mappings. Total STRINGS dict grew from 530 to 602 entries.
        - 100% coverage achieved for user-facing Arabic strings (verified by static analysis of every notify/error/tr/yesno/add_item call site).
        - Cleaned mixed-language Search labels: 'بحث Turkish' → 'بحث تركي' (Arabic-canonical, English mode shows "Search Turkish" via tr()).
        PERFORMANCE
        - meta_cache.get_many(): batch SQLite read for catalog rendering. An 80-item folder used to do 80 connection-open + PRAGMA + SELECT cycles; now it's one connection, one SELECT … IN (…). Microbench: 21.7ms → 0.8ms (26x faster) for 80 items.
        - Per-invocation settings cache (2s TTL): _get_setting()/_get_int_setting() in client.py used to construct a fresh xbmcaddon.Addon() and cross the Python↔C++ boundary on every call. Hot loops now O(1) after first read.
        - common.addon() instance cached with same 2s TTL. Same Python↔C++ boundary win for every consumer of addon().
        - orjson fast-path for JSON parsing when the package is available (2-5x faster on big Stremio catalog payloads). Graceful stdlib fallback when not installed.
        DIAGNOSTICS &amp; UX
        - New "Source diagnostics" action under Settings → Sources: probes every pinned manifest URL in parallel, reports response times color-coded (green/yellow/red), surfaces the slow source so you can find the bottleneck without reading logs.
        - Empty-folder state now explains why: "X of Y sources timed out — press to retry" with a one-tap retry button and a shortcut to source diagnostics.
        - Silent catalog failures now show a toast ("Could not reach &lt;name&gt; — skipped"), throttled to once per source per session.
        - tr() rewritten: O(1) hot path for exact matches + safer substring fallback that excludes 61 short keys to prevent in-word corruption (e.g. "تركي" no longer accidentally replaces inside "تركية").
        RESPONSIVENESS (this addresses "OK doesn't open the section" / slow folders)
        - Folder open now has a 5-second wall-clock budget — slow/hung catalogs no longer block the whole folder. Whatever returned inside 5s renders immediately.
        - fast_timeout('catalog') capped at 4s (was up to 10s). Catalog HTTP calls now fail fast instead of hanging the UI.
        - iter_parallel actually enforces its timeout via as_completed (was forwarding only to future.result, so a stuck future blocked the loop indefinitely).
        - Dispatch dedup window dropped 6s → 2.5s. Legitimate retries (back out, click again) no longer fail silently.
        - Suppressed play_item dispatches now show a toast notification so the user knows their click registered.
        DESIGN
        - Unified visual identity around logo palette (purple #7C3AED + cyan #33D8F7); replaced amber/charcoal in playback wait screen.
        - Brand top-accent on every dialog (purple → cyan gradient stripe).
        - Redesigned 14 home folder posters with consistent gradient + glyph + DEXHUB wordmark, language-neutral so they work for AR or EN.
        - Redesigned 8 home root icons (continue, search movies/series, sources, add, accounts, catalogs, next-up) on brand.
        - New clean fanart background (replaced chaotic AI-generated collage); subtle hex-grid + brand orbs + discreet wordmark.
        - Glassmorphism card on wait screen now actually uses brand-tinted layers (was solid black under amber).
        LOCALIZATION
        - New strings.po for English and Arabic with full settings labels + home folder titles + dialog strings + diagnostic strings (108 entries each).
        - settings.xml now uses $LOCALIZE references — switching the language flips every label, no restart.
        - Fixed Turkish/Korean home buckets that returned English in both modes; now Arabic-canonical with tr() resolution.
        - Auto-detect UI language from Kodi locale on first install (ar → Arabic, else English); preferred subtitle languages set accordingly.
        OTHER
        - Added LICENSE.txt (MIT) — addon.xml has always declared MIT but the file was missing.

==================================================
        v3.9.16 — Context filters everywhere:
        - Removed visible catalog filter toolbar rows; filters now live in long-press / context menu for cleaner lists.
        - Catalog filters are available from Sources, raw catalog lists, and items inside a catalog, not only Home folders.
        - Selecting a filter returns to the correct catalog/folder view and keeps global folder sorting/fallback playback from 3.9.15.

        v3.9.15 — Global folder sort + same-source fallback:
- Folder filters now merge all pinned catalog results first, then sort globally by release date, added date, title, or rating. Items are no longer grouped as source A then source B.
- Last Release / Last Added support dates from released/releaseInfo/dateAdded/createdAt/updatedAt and day/month values such as 21/4.
- Same-source fast play now tries the originating source first, then automatically falls back to the remaining sources if no playable links are found.

v3.9.13 — Folder tools and fast mode:
- Added one folder toolbar with folder filters, folder search, merged/source view toggle, duplicate toggle, same-source quick play toggle, folder refresh, and source ordering shortcut.
- Home folders can now hide duplicates using IMDb/TMDb/TVDb first, then title + year fallback.
- Folder search runs only inside the catalogs pinned to that folder for speed.
- Same-source quick play can be enabled per folder so movies open from the originating source without searching every source.
- Source priority is controlled by the pinned catalog order; the highest pinned source wins during duplicate removal.

v3.9.11 — Home pin + catalog filters:
- Source catalogs are pinned only to Home folders/Sub folders, not Collection.
- Added an in-catalog “Add this catalog to Home” button so pinning remains available after opening a catalog.
- Added per-pinned-catalog Filter buttons in Home folders; each button shows only extras supported by that Stremio catalog such as sort, Last Release or Last Added when available.
- Home folder direct content now applies each pinned catalog’s saved filter state.

v3.9.10 — Home sub folders:
- Added Sub folder support inside home folders such as Movies, Series, Arabic, Turkish and Korean.
- Source catalog context menu can pin catalogs directly into top-level folders or their Sub folders.
- Parent folders still show direct media from pinned catalogs; Sub folders are optional containers.
- Added Sub folder management actions from the home-folder context menu.

v3.9.7 — Turkish/Korean hub sections:
- Added Turkish and Korean home sections.
- Source catalog context menu can pin catalogs into Turkish/Korean.

v3.9.5 — Stremio Hub home:
- New clean home: متابعة، أفلام، مسلسلات، أنمي، بث مباشر، بحث، Sources، Collection.
- Home buckets are built dynamically from installed Stremio manifest catalogs.
- Source catalogs open fast direct listings by default; filters/folders stay in context menu.
- Add any catalog from Sources to Home folders/Sub folders via context menu.

v3.9.4 — POV-style Continue Watching:
- Continue Watching rows are playable direct resume items for home widgets, not folders.
- Added local POV progress-cache bridge from watched.db/traktcache4.db/mdblcache.db.
- Fixed playback crash: selected_subtitle_index undefined.
- Added VideoInfoTag resume points so Kodi skins show progress like POV.

v3.9.3 — Home sections hotfix:
- Provider home sections open direct listing (catalog_all) instead of folder/facet gate.
- Folder forcing for DexWorld Pro disabled by default.
- Genre/Year folder view disabled by default for POV-like behavior.

v3.9.1 — Settings overhaul + bilingual completeness + leaner wait dialog:
SETTINGS:
- Fixed duplicate tmdb_api_key (was in both General and TMDb Helper categories — Kodi only used one)
- Removed redundant poster_source_mode from UI (now derived automatically from default_meta_source)
- Reorganized into Metadata category: default_meta_source, fanarttv enrichment, all API keys in one place
- Converted all Arabic-only setting labels to English (matching the rest of the addon)
- Added "Clear metadata cache now" button
- Better section headers (Home screen, Click behavior, HTTP cache) with lsep dividers

LANGUAGE COMPLETENESS:
- Added 58 missing translations to STRINGS dict for previously-untranslated user-visible Arabic strings
- All add_item / notify / error calls now translate substring matches automatically
- Playback wait dialog status text and cancel hint now respect ui_language (was hardcoded bilingual)

PLAYBACK WAIT DIALOG (lighter &amp; faster):
- Background reduced from 6 layered images to 3 — same look, fewer GPU ops on open
- Removed duplicate progress bar glow layer (kept the sharp solid fill)
- Status text "CONNECTING" and cancel hint use Window.Property — single language at a time
- Fanart fade-in animation removed (was 600ms delay, no real visual benefit)

v3.9.0 — Major upgrade: speed + discovery + reliability:
NEW FEATURES:
- Discover menu: search history, people search (find any actor/director), episode calendar
- Search history: last 30 queries cached locally — pick from list instead of retyping
- People search: search TMDb for any actor/director and browse their full filmography
- Episode calendar: 2 modes — your Trakt watchlist OR all popular shows for the next 14 days
- AI subtitle quality feedback: thumbs-down sends data back to DexWorld to improve translations
- Plex/Emby/Jellyfin health monitor: background check every 5min, status visible to skin widgets

PERFORMANCE:
- SQLite metadata cache (POV-style): catalog re-renders go from ~800ms to ~50ms after first visit
- Smart TTL: old movies cached 6 months, ongoing shows refresh on next-air-date
- In-memory layer on top of disk for sub-millisecond reads
- Fanart.tv integration: lists now show clearart, banner, discart, multi-language clearlogo

INFRASTRUCTURE:
- Centralized logging module with automatic API key/token redaction in logs
- Per-host rate limiter (token bucket) for TMDb / Trakt / Cinemeta / Fanart.tv — prevents 429s on busy widgets
- Auto-tightens rate when upstream returns 429
- TMDb Helper handoff state machine refactored into single class (was 4 scattered properties)
- Subtitle files in special://temp now purged after 24h
- Meta cache + Fanart.tv expired rows purged hourly by service

NEW SETTINGS:
- Fanart.tv enrichment toggle + personal API key field
- TMDb API key (required for people search and discover features)
- DexWorld API key (for AI subtitles + feedback)
- Manual "Clear metadata cache" action button

- Playback wait window poster no longer crops the bottom of taller-than-2:3 posters (Korean / Asian drama covers)
- Reverted the ISA auto-injection from earlier 3.8.13 build — streams now play exactly as the provider sends them, no transparent format changes

v3.8.12 — performance &amp; robustness:
- Catalogs no longer render half-empty when an upstream returns a transient 502 (single retry on transient HTTP errors)
- Removed redundant filesystem syscall on every cache read/write (~60+ saved per catalog page)
- TMDb Helper local-DB lookups now run in read-only mode (~1-3ms faster each, ~30-60ms saved per render)
- Metadata-source picker preference cached per invocation (~15-30ms saved on 60-item catalogs)
- No changes to playback, source picker, or stop/back behaviour from 3.8.11 (plugin.py byte-identical)

v3.8.11:
- Fixed: addon no longer re-enters source search after Stop/Back when playback was already in progress
  (transient onPlayBackError events from Kodi are now ignored unless playback truly failed within the first minute)

v3.8.10:
- TMDb Helper integration overhaul: priority bumped, Arabic translation keys, fallback chain
- Player now passes poster/fanart/ar_title/ar_showname directly (fewer HTTP calls per click)
- Service-monitor fallback: works from widgets where IDs aren't in the URL
- Language flips apply without restart
- Stronger Stremio manifest validation with clear error messages
- Stale User-Agent strings unified to dynamic version
- Removed unused duplicate fanart images (-780 KB)

3.7.98
- Fix AIOStreams/Torrentio source discovery: query all stream providers and preserve imdb/tmdb ids for torrent addons.
- Source picker now waits for all stream providers instead of stopping after the first addon returns results.

3.7.92
- إصلاح الاستئناف المباشر من Continue Watching: صار يمرّر resume_percent و source_provider_id، ويشغل مسار Player.play عند وجود استئناف حتى يثبت seek مثل النسخ القديمة.
- دعم resume_percent في التشغيل التلقائي للأفلام والحلقات، وليس فقط نافذة اختيار المصدر.
- تحسين fanart الحقيقي للفيلم/المسلسل في Continue Watching وNext Up وFavorites، مع حفظ الخلفية في الكاش حتى تظهر في الزيارات التالية.
3.7.91
- إصلاح متابعة المشاهدة: عناصر Trakt كانت تُشغّل من بداية الفيديو بدل من الموضع المحفوظ. السبب جذرياً كان في `import_progress`: استدعاء `/sync/playback/movies` و `/sync/playback/episodes` بدون `?extended=full`، فـ Trakt ما يرجع `runtime`، ومنه `position = duration × progress / 100 = 0`. أضفت `?extended=full` لكلا الاستدعاءين.
- حماية إضافية لصفوف قديمة في DB ما عندها position دقيق: تمرير `resume_percent` عبر URL/cache ctx، و`_post_start_chores` يحسب الموضع تلقائياً من `player.getTotalTime() × percent / 100` لمّا يبدأ التشغيل. يضمن أن أي صف فيه `percent &gt; 1%` يتم استئنافه صح حتى لو `position` صفر.
- استخدام expli­cit none-check بدل `or` للموضع، لتجنب اعتبار `0.0` فعلية كـ "غير محدد".
3.7.90
- إصلاح حرج: NameError "poster_source_mode" كان يفجّر فتح أي عنصر من Continue Watching أو streams (موجود من قبل، اللوج كشفه). الدالة كانت مستخدمة في `_meta_cache_discriminator` بدون استيراد. أُضيف لقائمة الـ imports من art.
- إصلاح Next Up: البوسترات والبانرز ما تظهر — كان السبب أن `_trakt_art_bundle` و `_art_bundle_for_ids` يرجعون poster='' في وضع "محلي فقط" (وهو الافتراضي)، رغم أن صفوف Next Up افتراضية وما عندها provider محلي. الحل: تمرير `force_remote=True` لكل استدعاء من Next Up.
- اكتشاف روابط Plex/Emby tokenized المنتهية في الكاش وتجاهلها — قبل كان البوستر القديم يعرض حتى لو ما يشتغل، يحجب البحث عن بديل.
- نقل تحميل صور Next Up إلى inline بدل background thread، فالصور تظهر من أول فتح بدل ما تحتاج إعادة فتح للقائمة.
- استمرار حفظ الصور المحلولة في playback_store حتى الفتحات اللاحقة تكون فورية.
3.7.89
- إصلاح حرج: تغيير مصدر الميتاداتا (Cinemeta/TMDb Helper/Trakt) لإضافات Plex/Plexio/Emby ما كان يأثر فعلياً، والبوسترات تطلع مكسورة. السبب: `_normalize_meta_art_urls` كان يلفّ بوستر TMDb داخل `/photo/:/transcode?url=...` التابع لخادم Plex، وPlex ما يقدر يحلّ URL خارجي.
- الآن: لمّا تختار مصدر صريح، الإضافة تحترم البوستر الجديد كما هو وما تعيد كتابته عبر الخادم الأصلي.
- إضافة فحص host مطابق لـ `_plexmod_transcode_url` كحماية ثانية: روابط من نطاقات خارجية ما تنلف أبداً عبر Plex transcode.
- مسح فوري لطبقة الكاش `_META_MEM` بعد كل تغيير لمصدر الميتاداتا، حتى تظهر النتيجة بدون إعادة فتح Kodi.
- إزالة تعريفات مكررة لـ `_meta_mem_key/get/put` من plugin.py.
3.7.83
- Added official DexWorld IPTV and DexWorld Subtitles public service links to Quick Start and support info.
- Kept Plexio/StreamBridge as configured/private manifest services without embedding keys.

3.7.82
- DexWorld recommended sources now use public setup sites only (Plexio + StreamBridge/Emby); no private tokens are bundled
- New DexHub fan art background
- Added bilingual DexWorld support/trial info (@a6ahd)
3.7.73
- Wait screen v6: cinematic full-bleed fanart 45%, 3-layer amber glow poster, glassmorphism card
- Wait screen v6: dual-layer progress bar (solid + glow), 12px wave bars, cyan pulse dot
- Wait screen v6: cancel hint inline with wave bars, cleaner layout
3.7.72
- Sources: 8 badge slots (was 4), badges 26px tall (was 20px)
- Sources: native badge fallback — HDR/DV/Atmos/4K always show without preset JSON
- Sources: video_bits + audio_bits exposed as list properties + shown in row 3
- Sources: size chip top-right, quality band redesigned with 100px height
- wait screen: setImage() method for poster (fixes blank poster on CDN Plex)
- Icons: full premium set — continue, nextup, favorites, sources, add, settings, accounts
3.7.71
- New premium icon set: continue, nextup, favorites, sources, add, settings, accounts, catalogs, search
- Provider icons redesigned: Plex (gold), Emby (green), Trakt (red), TMDb (cyan-green)
- Search screen fanart: custom DexHub hex-grid background
- All icons match DexHub dark aesthetic (charcoal + amber + cyan + purple)
3.7.70
- Wait screen: poster/clearlogo/fanart now applied via setImage() — fixes blank poster with Plex/CDN URLs
- Wait screen: clearlogo shown via setImage(), falls back to text title when absent
- Resume: _post_start_chores always runs (not conditional); seek retries up to 6x with adaptive wait
- Resume: 25s timeout (was 20s) for slow CDN streams to buffer before giving up on seek
- HOTFIX: remove broken image:// wrapper that hid all provider icons in 3.7.69
- provider_art: keep relative URL → base_url resolution (harmless, for edge cases)
3.7.69
- New fanart/background: DexHub brand artwork
- Nextup: renders immediately, art backfill runs in background thread (no more waiting)
- Provider icons: relative logo URLs resolved against base_url (fixes CDN Plex servers)
- Provider icons: image:// wrapper for remote logos (Kodi image cache, no re-download)
- Providers list: background manifest refresh for entries with missing logo
- _clean_art_value: relative paths starting with / now accepted
3.7.68
- TMDb Helper source: hits local DB first (zero network), falls back to live API
- Nextup: parallel art resolve + write-back to playback_store (instant on 2nd visit)
- Favorites: shared _resolve_row_art chain: row → TMDb Helper DB → trakt → tmdb_direct
- Clearlogo no longer overwritten when changing metadata source
- _fetch_from_tmdb_helper now tries installed TMDb Helper DB before any API call
3.7.67
- Meta source picker now actually applies on every item (was skipped when item had a poster)
- Meta cache purged on source change so the next listing reflects the new pick instantly
- Continue Watching: stale-flag on Window(10000) so home rebuilds even after navigating away
- Favorites posters: Trakt-only canonical IDs (trakt:N, slug:...) now resolved correctly
- Wait screen: properties pushed to global Window(10000) so $INFO actually finds the poster
- Wait screen: properties cleared on close to prevent leak between sessions
3.7.66
- Wait screen v4: clearer status text + real progress bar, ctx now wins over TMDb DB
- Wait screen now shows on setResolvedUrl path too (was Player.play only)
- Cross-invocation dispatch de-dup: TMDb Helper, play_item, play no longer fire twice on double-tap
- Favorites posters: parallel resolve (8 threads) + write-back to SQLite for instant 2nd visit
- Continue Watching now refreshes home/CW container automatically when playback ends
- Sources window: skip TMDb backfill when meta complete; poll interval 750ms → 500ms
- Wait window open stall 160ms → 60ms
3.7.62
- Fix: keep TMDb Helper handoff flag alive until real playback lifecycle events
- Fix: source browser/wait/player now prefer TMDb Helper poster + clearlogo, with source/XML fallback
- Tweak: playback wait layout refined for clearer logo + loader alignment</news>
        <assets>
            <icon>resources/media/icon.png</icon>
            <fanart>resources/media/fanart.jpg</fanart>
        </assets>
    </extension>
</addon>
